2002-01-05	O

Saudi	B-LOC
Arabia	I-LOC
(	O
SA	O
)	O

International	O
;	O
military	O
;	O
terrorism	O

The	O
Riyadh-based	B-MISC
Naif	B-ORG
Arab	I-ORG
Academy	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
Security	I-ORG
Sciences	I-ORG
said	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
running	O
a	O
two-week	O
workshop	O
for	O
50	O
anti-terrorism	O
experts	O
.	O

On	O
5	O
January	O
2002	O
pan-Arab	O
anti-terror	O
academy	O
Naif	B-ORG
Arab	I-ORG
Academy	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
Security	I-ORG
Sciences	I-ORG
reopened	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
since	O
the	O
September	O
2001	O
terror	O
attacks	O
on	O
the	O
US	B-LOC
.	O

Naif	B-ORG
Arab	I-ORG
Academy	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
Security	I-ORG
Sciences	I-ORG
is	O
based	O
in	O
Riyadh	B-LOC
.	O

Naif	B-ORG
Arab	I-ORG
Academy	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
Security	I-ORG
Sciences	I-ORG
is	O
run	O
by	O
an	O
Arab	B-MISC
Interior	O
Ministers'	B-ORG
Council	I-ORG
.	O

In	O
a	O
statement	O
Naif	B-ORG
Arab	I-ORG
Academy	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
Security	I-ORG
Sciences	I-ORG
announced	O
--	O

It	O
will	O
sponsor	O
a	O
2-week	O
workshop	O
for	O
50	O
anti-terrorism	O
experts	O
.	O

The	O
workshop	O
's	O
anti-terrorism	O
experts	O
are	O
from	O
11	O
Arab	B-MISC
countries	O
including	O
Algeria	B-LOC
,	O
Bahrain	B-LOC
,	O
Egypt	B-LOC
,	O
Jordan	B-LOC
,	O
Lebanon	B-LOC
,	O
Mauritania	B-LOC
,	O
Morocco	B-LOC
,	O
Saudi	B-LOC
Arabia	I-LOC
,	O
Sudan	B-LOC
,	O
Syria	B-LOC
and	O
Yemen	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
workshop	O
's	O
anti-terrorism	O
experts	O
belong	O
to	O
anti-terror	O
squads	O
in	O
Arab	B-MISC
security	O
agencies	O
and	O
Anti-Organized	B-ORG
Crime	I-ORG
Units	I-ORG
.	O

Some	O
specialize	O
in	O
dealing	O
with	O
kidnapping	O
and	O
hostage-taking	O
scenarios	O
.	O

The	O
workshop	O
will	O
address	O
several	O
terrorism-related	O
issues	O
including	O
political	O
factors	O
leading	O
to	O
terror	O
,	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
religion	O
in	O
fighting	O
terrorists	O
and	O
economic	O
factors	O
that	O
support	O
crime	O
and	O
terrorism	O
.	O

The	O
workshop	O
will	O
study	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
the	O
Internet	B-MISC
to	O
promote	O
terrorism	O
and	O
the	O
Internet	B-MISC
's	O
role	O
in	O
facilitating	O
money	O
transactions	O
and	O
funding	O
terrorist	O
groups	O
.	O

In	O
April	O
1998	O
Arab	B-MISC
countries	O
signed	O
an	O
anti-terrorism	O
agreement	O
that	O
binds	O
the	O
signatories	O
to	O
coordinate	O
to	O
fight	O
terrorism	O
.	O

2002-01-07	O

proliferation	O
;	O
international	O

A	O
United	B-ORG
Nation	I-ORG
nuclear	O
team	O
will	O
make	O
a	O
week-long	O
visit	O
to	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
this	O
weekend	O
to	O
inspect	O
the	O
Stalinist	B-MISC
state	O
's	O
controversial	O
nuclear	O
site	O
.	O

Government	O
sources	O
said	O
on	O
January	O
7	O
,	O
2002	O
that	O
a	O
united	O
nation	O
nuclear	O
team	O
will	O
make	O
a	O
week-long	O
visit	O
to	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
this	O
weekend	O
to	O
inspect	O
the	O
Stalinist	B-MISC
state	O
's	O
controversial	O
nuclear	O
site	O
.	O

The	O
upcoming	O
visit	O
is	O
viewed	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
International	B-ORG
Atomic	I-ORG
Energy	I-ORG
Agency	I-ORG
(	O
IAEA	B-ORG
)	O
drive	O
to	O
clarify	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
nuclear	O
ambitions	O
.	O

A	O
government	O
source	O
stated	O
the	O
visit	O
by	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
IAEA	B-ORG
safety	O
experts	O
is	O
scheduled	O
to	O
last	O
for	O
a	O
week	O
beginning	O
January	O
12	O
,	O
2002	O
.	O

The	O
source	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
inspection	O
would	O
focus	O
on	O
an	O
isotope	O
production	O
laboratory	O
in	O
the	O
Yongbyon	B-LOC
nuclear	O
complex	O
which	O
is	O
north	O
of	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
capital	O
Pyongyang	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
IAEA	B-ORG
tour	O
of	O
the	O
isotope	O
production	O
laboratory	O
will	O
unlikely	O
give	O
a	O
full	O
picture	O
of	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
suspected	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
ambitions	O
.	O

The	O
tour	O
was	O
a	O
surprise	O
offer	O
made	O
by	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
in	O
November	O
2001	O
.	O

IAEA	B-ORG
accepted	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
proposal	O
last	O
month	O
but	O
cautioned	O
that	O
the	O
proposal	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
breakthrough	O
.	O

IAEA	B-ORG
also	O
stated	O
the	O
lab	O
is	O
not	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
frozen	O
facilities	O
it	O
wants	O
to	O
look	O
into	O
.	O

IAEA	B-ORG
is	O
based	O
in	O
Vienna	B-LOC
and	O
is	O
the	O
UN	B-ORG
's	O
nuclear	O
supervisor	O
.	O

North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
has	O
denied	O
the	O
IAEA	B-ORG
full	O
access	O
to	O
its	O
facilities	O
.	O

North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
froze	O
its	O
suspected	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
program	O
at	O
Yongbyon	B-LOC
in	O
exchange	O
for	O
receiving	O
two	O
nuclear	O
reactors	O
producing	O
less	O
weapons-grade	O
plutonium	O
under	O
a	O
1994	O
accord	O
with	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
4.6-billion-dollar	O
project	O
was	O
due	O
to	O
be	O
completed	O
by	O
2003	O
.	O

Delays	O
have	O
pushed	O
back	O
the	O
finish	O
until	O
at	O
least	O
2008	O
.	O

Pyongyang	B-LOC
insists	O
it	O
will	O
allow	O
full	O
IAEA	B-ORG
inspections	O
only	O
when	O
a	O
significant	O
portion	O
of	O
the	O
project	O
as	O
defined	O
in	O
the	O
1994	O
accord	O
is	O
completed	O
.	O

2002-01-11	O

South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
(	O
KR	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
politics	O
;	O
Telecom	O

They	O
threatened	O
an	O
Internet	B-MISC
war	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
campaign	O
to	O
defend	O
the	O
traditional	O
cuisine	O
.	O

They	O
threatened	O
an	O
Internet	B-MISC
war	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
campaign	O
to	O
defend	O
the	O
traditional	O
cuisine	O
.	O

A	O
nationalist	O
group	O
has	O
vowed	O
cyber	O
hostilities	O
against	O
U.S.	B-LOC
based	O
media	O
company	O
Warner	B-ORG
Bros.	I-ORG
and	O
one	O
of	O
France	B-LOC
's	O
state-run	O
television	O
channels	O
.	O

The	O
activists	O
accuse	O
the	O
organizations	O
of	O
being	O
culturally-biased	O
and	O
insulting	O
.	O

A	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
group	O
has	O
announced	O
a	O
campaign	O
backed	O
by	O
food	O
scientists	O
to	O
promote	O
the	O
eating	O
of	O
dog	O
meat	O
.	O

This	O
announcement	O
was	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
increasing	O
foreign	O
criticism	O
of	O
the	O
way	O
dogs	O
are	O
slaughtered	O
in	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
killing	O
of	O
dogs	O
for	O
restaurants	O
has	O
become	O
a	O
more	O
popular	O
topic	O
than	O
the	O
football	O
World	B-MISC
Cup	I-MISC
finals	O
.	O

The	B-MISC
World	B-MISC
Cup	I-MISC
finals	O
are	O
to	O
be	O
co-hosted	O
by	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
and	O
Japan	B-LOC
this	O
year	O
.	O

The	O
debate	O
was	O
partly	O
fueled	O
by	O
FIFA	B-ORG
,	O
football	O
's	O
international	O
governing	O
body	O
.	O

FIFA	B-ORG
urged	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
to	O
prevent	O
the	O
inhumane	O
killing	O
of	O
dogs	O
.	O

The	O
organizers	O
of	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
website	O
antijapan.wo.ro	O
vowed	O
to	O
paralyze	O
the	O
websites	O
of	O
Warner	B-ORG
Bros	I-ORG
.	O

(	O
www.wpix.com	O
)	O
and	O
the	O
French	B-MISC
state	O
television	O
network	O
(	O
www.francetv.fr	O
)	O
on	O
January	O
19	O
,	O
2002	O
.	O

The	O
organizers	O
of	O
the	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
website	O
accused	O
the	O
broadcasters	O
of	O
falsely	O
describing	O
South	B-MISC
Koreans	I-MISC
and	O
their	O
food	O
culture	O
as	O
barbaric	O
.	O

The	O
anti-Japan	O
group	O
stated	O
that	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
culture	O
is	O
under	O
attack	O
.	O

The	O
statement	O
was	O
made	O
to	O
gain	O
supporters	O
to	O
join	O
the	O
lobbying	O
.	O

Cyber	O
warfare	O
has	O
become	O
a	O
common	O
weapon	O
for	O
South	B-MISC
Koreans	I-MISC
.	O

They	O
are	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
Internet	B-MISC
savvy	O
nations	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
cyber	O
campaigners	O
disabled	O
Japanese	B-MISC
education	O
ministry	O
websites	O
last	O
year	O
in	O
a	O
protest	O
against	O
history	O
books	O
accused	O
of	O
skimming	O
Japan	B-LOC
's	O
wartime	O
record	O
in	O
Asia	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
nationalist	O
group	O
was	O
formed	O
to	O
campaign	O
against	O
Japan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
group	O
said	O
the	O
foreign	O
broadcasters	O
are	O
battering	O
the	O
eating	O
dogmeat	O
culture	O
and	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
insulting	O
behavior	O
.	O

It	O
tramples	O
on	O
a	O
tradition	O
of	O
one	O
country	O
.	O

The	O
group	O
said	O
the	O
foreign	O
broadcasters	O
do	O
not	O
show	O
any	O
remorse	O
for	O
their	O
culture	O
of	O
eating	O
snails	O
and	O
horses	O
.	O

The	O
cyber	O
attack	O
is	O
to	O
show	O
the	O
power	O
of	O
South	B-MISC
Koreans	I-MISC
and	O
Asians	B-MISC
against	O
the	O
West	B-LOC
's	O
sense	O
of	O
superiority	O
and	O
ignorance	O
of	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
history	O
.	O

Another	O
group	O
said	O
they	O
will	O
launch	O
an	O
association	O
next	O
Monday	O
of	O
around	O
100	O
dog	O
meat	O
restaurant	O
owners	O
in	O
the	O
Seoul	B-LOC
region	O
and	O
hold	O
a	O
seminar	O
to	O
promote	O
the	O
dish	O
.	O

Food	O
scientist	O
at	O
Chung	B-ORG
Chong	I-ORG
College	I-ORG
an	O
Yong-geun	B-PER
said	O
he	O
would	O
introduce	O
some	O
350	O
different	O
kinds	O
of	O
culinary	O
art	O
with	O
dog	O
meat	O
.	O

French	B-MISC
actress-turned	O
activist	O
Brigitte	B-PER
Bardot	I-PER
and	O
other	O
animal	O
rights	O
campaigners	O
call	O
to	O
stop	O
the	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
practice	O
of	O
eating	O
dogs	O
.	O

FIFA	B-ORG
president	O
Sepp	B-PER
Blatter	I-PER
sent	O
a	O
letter	O
last	O
November	O
to	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
World	B-MISC
Cup	I-MISC
organizing	O
committee	O
calling	O
for	O
immediate	O
and	O
decisive	O
measures	O
against	O
cruelty	O
to	O
dogs	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
ahead	O
of	O
the	O
World	B-MISC
Cup	I-MISC
which	O
starts	O
May	O
31	O
,	O
2002	O
.	O

Head	O
of	O
the	O
Korean	B-MISC
Football	B-ORG
Association	I-ORG
and	O
a	O
FIFA	B-ORG
vice	O
president	O
Chung	B-PER
Mong-Joon	I-PER
said	O
FIFA	B-ORG
should	O
not	O
intervene	O
in	O
the	O
eating	O
habits	O
of	O
a	O
sovereign	O
nation	O
.	O

South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
officials	O
said	O
most	O
dogs	O
used	O
for	O
eating	O
were	O
killed	O
instantly	O
by	O
electrocution	O
.	O

Activists	O
contend	O
many	O
slaughterhouses	O
in	O
the	O
countryside	O
are	O
not	O
controlled	O
.	O

They	O
strangle	O
dogs	O
,	O
hang	O
them	O
by	O
a	O
rope	O
and	O
beat	O
them	O
in	O
line	O
with	O
traditional	O
practice	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
meat	O
more	O
tender	O
.	O

Dog	O
restaurants	O
were	O
told	O
to	O
close	O
or	O
go	O
into	O
the	O
backstreets	O
when	O
Seoul	B-LOC
hosted	O
the	O
1988	O
Olympics	B-MISC
.	O

No	O
similar	O
move	O
is	O
planned	O
for	O
the	O
World	B-MISC
Cup	I-MISC
.	O

The	O
authorities	O
say	O
the	O
practice	O
is	O
slowly	O
disappearing	O
in	O
Korea	B-LOC
.	O

A	O
recent	O
survey	O
stated	O
that	O
about	O
one	O
million	O
dogs	O
are	O
sold	O
every	O
year	O
for	O
food	O
in	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
and	O
92	O
percent	O
of	O
men	O
aged	O
20	O
and	O
above	O
and	O
68	O
percent	O
of	O
adult	O
women	O
have	O
tasted	O
dog	O
meat	O
.	O

2002-01-15	O

Pakistan	B-LOC
(	O
PK	O
)	O
;	O
India	B-LOC
(	O
IN	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
Government	O
;	O
terrorism	O
;	O
war	O
and	O
conflict	O
;	O
dissent	O
;	O
leader	O

Newspapers	O
and	O
magazines	O
extolling	O
the	O
virtues	O
of	O
Islamic	B-MISC
holy	O
war	O
in	O
Kashmir	B-LOC
continue	O
to	O
fill	O
the	O
newstands	O
in	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
despite	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
military	O
Government	O
's	O
attempt	O
at	O
a	O
large	O
scale	O
containment	O
of	O
religious	O
extremism	O
.	O

Around	O
1400	O
alleged	O
religious	O
extremists	O
have	O
been	O
arrested	O
since	O
020112	O
under	O
severe	O
actions	O
against	O
Islamic	B-MISC
militants	O
and	O
sectarian	O
radicals	O
announced	O
by	O
President	O
Pervez	B-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
during	O
the	O
weekend	O
.	O

The	O
severe	O
actions	O
against	O
militants	O
and	O
radicals	O
came	O
as	O
Pervez	B-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
banned	O
5	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
.	O

The	O
banned	O
5	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
included	O
the	O
2	O
hardline	O
militant	O
groups	O
fighting	O
Indian	B-MISC
rule	O
in	O
Kashmir	B-LOC
which	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
government	O
accuses	O
of	O
staging	O
the	O
violent	O
011213	O
attack	O
on	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
parliament	O
.	O

Pakistani	B-MISC
authorities	O
have	O
stated	O
that	O
no	O
statements	O
or	O
literature	O
from	O
the	O
5	O
banned	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
would	O
be	O
tolerated	O
after	O
Pervez	B-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
's	O
speech	O
banning	O
the	O
5	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
.	O

Pervez	B-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
's	O
speech	O
banning	O
the	O
5	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
was	O
applauded	O
by	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
.	O

Iftikhar	B-PER
Ahmed	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
under	O
the	O
notification	O
that	O
was	O
issued	O
late	O
at	O
night	O
on	O
020114	O
all	O
publications	O
,	O
newspapers	O
,	O
weekly	O
magazines	O
,	O
monthlies	O
,	O
etc	O
of	O
the	O
5	O
banned	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
are	O
banned	O
and	O
confiscated	O
.	O

Iftikhar	B-PER
Ahmed	I-PER
is	O
a	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
interior	O
ministry	O
official	O
.	O

Iftikhar	B-PER
Ahmed	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
's	O
provincial	O
governments	O
have	O
been	O
asked	O
to	O
implement	O
the	O
orders	O
in	O
the	O
notification	O
that	O
was	O
issued	O
on	O
020114	O
and	O
that	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
's	O
provincial	O
governments	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
taking	O
action	O
.	O

Karachi	B-LOC
police	O
chief	O
Tariq	B-PER
Jamil	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
5	O
banned	O
Islamic	B-MISC
groups	O
would	O
not	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
operate	O
in	O
any	O
way	O
.	O

Tariq	B-PER
Jamil	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
he	O
would	O
examine	O
if	O
the	O
baned	O
literature	O
is	O
still	O
available	O
in	O
the	O
market	O
despite	O
the	O
ban	O
.	O

The	O
2	O
hardline	O
militant	O
groups	O
fighting	O
Indian	B-MISC
rule	O
in	O
Kashmir	B-LOC
are	O
the	O
Lashkar-e-Taiba	B-MISC
and	O
Jaish-e-Mohammad	B-MISC
.	O

The	O
Lashkar-e-Taiba	B-MISC
and	O
Jaish-e-Mohammad	B-MISC
are	O
still	O
distributing	O
their	O
message	O
through	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
publications	O
and	O
magazines	O
easily	O
available	O
in	O
Karachi	B-LOC
.	O

Other	O
groups	O
linked	O
to	O
terrorism	O
and	O
included	O
on	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
Terrorist	O
Exclusion	O
List	O
are	O
also	O
publishing	O
regular	O
newspapers	O
and	O
journals	O
containing	O
rhetoric	O
that	O
is	O
against	O
Western	B-MISC
countries	O
and	O
calls	O
for	O
war	O
in	O
the	O
name	O
of	O
Islam	B-MISC
.	O

Qari	O
Mohammad	B-PER
Zafar	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
his	O
elders	O
urged	O
him	O
to	O
read	O
about	O
Jihad	O
through	O
the	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
published	O
by	O
the	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
and	O
Lashkar-i-Taiba	B-ORG
's	O
zarb-e-Taiba	O
weekly	O
.	O

Qari	O
Mohammad	B-PER
Zafar	I-PER
is	O
an	O
18-year-old	O
student	O
of	O
a	O
religious	O
seminary	O
.	O

Qari	O
Mohammad	B-PER
Zafar	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
he	O
did	O
not	O
know	O
whether	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
government	O
will	O
also	O
ban	O
the	O
publications	O
encouraging	O
Jihad	O
.	O

Qari	O
Mohammad	B-PER
Zafar	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
himself	O
and	O
other	O
people	O
have	O
been	O
told	O
by	O
our	O
elders	O
to	O
read	O
pro-Jihad	O
newspapers	O
and	O
magazines	O
.	O

The	O
al-Rashid	O
Trust	O
and	O
Lashkar-i-Taiba	B-ORG
are	O
on	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
Terrorist	O
Exclusion	O
List	O
and	O
the	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
's	O
and	O
Lashkar-i-Taiba	B-ORG
's	O
assets	O
frozen	O
in	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
has	O
not	O
been	O
officially	O
banned	O
in	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
primary	O
editorial	O
in	O
The	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
of	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
on	O
020115	O
carried	O
a	O
warning	O
to	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
government	O
.	O

The	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
of	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
supports	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
Fund	I-ORG
linked	O
to	O
Osama	B-PER
bin	I-PER
Laden	I-PER
's	O
al-Qaeda	O
network	O
.	O

The	O
headline	O
in	O
the	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
of	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
on	O
020115	O
stated	O
action	O
extreme	O
against	O
extremism	O
above	O
an	O
article	O
stating	O
that	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
government	O
should	O
not	O
domineer	O
a	O
large	O
section	O
of	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
society	O
which	O
supported	O
the	O
jihad	O
against	O
Indian	B-MISC
rule	O
in	O
the	O
divided	O
Himalayan	B-MISC
state	O
of	O
Kashmir	B-LOC
.	O

Newspaper	O
seller	O
Mohammad	B-PER
Farooq	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Pervez	B-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
's	O
clamp-down	O
on	O
extremism	O
had	O
done	O
little	O
to	O
limit	O
the	O
demand	O
for	O
banned	O
religious	O
extremist	O
publications	O
.	O

Mohammad	B-PER
Farooq	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
publication	O
of	O
the	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
of	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
has	O
not	O
been	O
affected	O
yet	O
by	O
Pervez	B-PER
Musharraf	I-PER
's	O
clamp-down	O
on	O
extremism	O
and	O
the	O
circulation	O
of	O
the	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
of	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
has	O
increased	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
couple	O
of	O
days	O
.	O

Over	O
12	O
publications	O
including	O
dailies	O
,	O
weeklies	O
and	O
monthlies	O
of	O
various	O
extremist	O
groups	O
including	O
those	O
banned	O
on	O
020112	O
still	O
sell	O
in	O
large	O
numbers	O
in	O
the	O
markets	O
and	O
bazaars	O
of	O
Karachi	B-LOC
.	O

Police	O
officer	O
Mohammad	B-PER
Iqbal	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
police	O
so	O
far	O
have	O
not	O
received	O
any	O
instructions	O
to	O
take	O
action	O
against	O
any	O
banned	O
religious	O
extremist	O
publications	O
.	O

Analysts	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
government	O
may	O
have	O
trouble	O
explaining	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
government	O
's	O
reasoning	O
if	O
the	O
banned	O
religious	O
extremist	O
groups'	O
publications	O
are	O
suddenly	O
removed	O
from	O
the	O
newsstands	O
because	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
Government	O
generally	O
supports	O
the	O
freedom	O
of	O
the	O
press	O
.	O

A	O
reporter	O
who	O
did	O
not	O
want	O
to	O
be	O
named	O
from	O
the	O
publication	O
of	O
the	O
Islam	B-MISC
daily	O
of	O
Al-Rashid	B-ORG
Trust	I-ORG
stated	O
that	O
it	O
would	O
not	O
be	O
easy	O
for	O
the	O
Pakistani	B-MISC
government	O
to	O
ban	O
the	O
religious	O
extremist	O
publications	O
and	O
make	O
over	O
500	O
employees	O
jobless	O
.	O

2002-01-17	O

Iran	B-LOC
(	O
IR	B-ORG
)	O

Narcotics	O
;	O
military	O

Thirteen	O
drug	O
traffickers	O
were	O
killed	O
and	O
10	O
arrested	O
in	O
Iran	B-LOC
anti-drug	O
sweeps	O
.	O

The	O
Iranian	B-MISC
army	O
launched	O
a	O
huge	O
sweep	O
against	O
traffickers	O
along	O
the	O
borders	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
.	O

On	O
January	O
17	O
,	O
2002	O
a	O
state	O
radio	O
reported	O
that	O
thirteen	O
drug	O
traffickers	O
were	O
killed	O
and	O
10	O
arrested	O
in	O
Iran	B-LOC
anti-drug	O
sweeps	O
.	O

The	O
Iranian	B-MISC
army	O
launched	O
a	O
huge	O
sweep	O
against	O
traffickers	O
along	O
the	O
borders	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
radio	O
said	O
the	O
first	O
day	O
of	O
Val	B-PER
Fajr	I-PER
accumulated	O
more	O
than	O
four	O
tons	O
of	O
drugs	O
and	O
50	O
guns	O
in	O
southeast	O
Iran	B-LOC
on	O
January	O
16	O
,	O
2002	O
.	O

Val	B-PER
Fajr	I-PER
means	O
swear	O
to	O
victory	O
in	O
Arabic	B-MISC
and	O
is	O
a	O
phrase	O
from	O
the	O
Koran	B-MISC
.	O

In	O
December	O
2002	O
police	O
announced	O
than	O
an	O
armed	O
corps	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
,	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
Turkmenistan	B-LOC
was	O
being	O
assembled	O
specifically	O
to	O
combat	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
along	O
Iran	B-LOC
's	O
borders	O
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
is	O
a	O
major	O
transit	O
point	O
between	O
drug	O
producers	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
markets	O
of	O
Europe	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
Gulf	B-LOC
.	O

Parliament	O
approved	O
plans	O
in	O
May	O
2001	O
to	O
build	O
an	O
anti-drugs	O
wall	O
along	O
the	O
925-kilometre	O
(	O
560-mile	O
)	O
border	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

A	O
budget	O
was	O
allocated	O
for	O
the	O
barrier	O
to	O
be	O
equipped	O
with	O
electronic	O
detention	O
equipment	O
.	O

An	O
Afghan	B-MISC
television	O
reported	O
on	O
January	O
16	O
,	O
2002	O
that	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
interim	O
administration	O
has	O
banned	O
the	O
cultivation	O
of	O
opium	O
poppies	O
in	O
a	O
bid	O
to	O
end	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

In	O
July	O
2000	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
militia	O
also	O
banned	O
production	O
of	O
opium	O
.	O

Opium	O
is	O
the	O
raw	O
ingredient	O
for	O
heroin	O
.	O

The	O
ban	O
was	O
strictly	O
enforced	O
with	O
opium	O
production	O
decreasing	O
from	O
3,200	O
tons	O
to	O
185	O
tons	O
.	O

Afghan	B-MISC
farmers	O
resumed	O
growing	O
opium	O
poppies	O
after	O
the	O
militia	O
was	O
overthrown	O
in	O
December	O
2001	O
.	O

Iranian	B-MISC
law	O
states	O
the	O
death	O
penalty	O
for	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

More	O
than	O
3,000	O
policemen	O
have	O
been	O
killed	O
in	O
anti-drugs	O
raids	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
20	O
years	O
.	O

2002-01-23	O

Iran	B-LOC
(	O
IR	B-ORG
)	O
;	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
(	O
AF	O
)	O
;	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
(	O
PK	B-LOC
)	O

Narcotics	O
;	O
military	O

Iranian	B-MISC
army	O
arrests	O
1600	O
drug	O
traffickers	O
,	O
kills	O
21	O
,	O
and	O
seizes	O
6	O
tons	O
of	O
drugs	O
and	O
weapons	O
in	O
large-scale	O
operation	O
along	O
its	O
borders	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
Government	O
has	O
banned	O
cultivation	O
of	O
opium	O
poppies	O
and	O
plans	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
wall	O
along	O
its	O
border	O
in	O
an	O
attempt	O
to	O
end	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
's	O
state	O
news	O
agency	O
IRNA	B-ORG
reported	O
23	O
January	O
2002	O
that	O
Iranian	B-MISC
security	O
forces	O
killed	O
21	O
drug	O
traffickers	O
and	O
arrested	O
more	O
than	O
1600	O
in	O
operations	O
in	O
the	O
east	O
and	O
south	O
of	O
Iran	B-LOC
in	O
recent	O
days	O
.	O

IRNA	B-ORG
stated	O
that	O
in	O
the	O
large-scale	O
army	O
operation	O
along	O
the	O
eastern	O
borders	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
21	O
drug	O
traffickers	O
were	O
killed	O
,	O
1500	O
arrested	O
and	O
approximately	O
5	O
tons	O
of	O
drugs	O
seized	O
.	O

IRNA	B-ORG
stated	O
that	O
the	O
10-day-old	O
operation	O
would	O
continue	O
until	O
all	O
the	O
traffickers	O
were	O
killed	O
or	O
arrested	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
separate	O
dispatch	O
IRNA	B-ORG
stated	O
that	O
during	O
the	O
past	O
20	O
days	O
in	O
southern	O
Iran	B-LOC
's	O
Fars	B-ORG
Province	I-ORG
police	O
had	O
arrested	O
107	O
drug	O
traffickers	O
including	O
11	O
foreign	O
nationals	O
.	O

The	O
nationalities	O
of	O
the	O
foreigners	O
were	O
not	O
mentioned	O
.	O

IRNA	B-ORG
stated	O
that	O
approximately	O
1	O
ton	O
of	O
various	O
drugs	O
including	O
hashish	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
fire	O
arms	O
were	O
seized	O
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
is	O
a	O
major	O
transit	O
point	O
between	O
drug	O
producers	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
markets	O
of	O
Europe	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
Gulf	B-LOC
.	O

In	O
May	O
2001	O
the	O
Iranian	B-MISC
parliament	O
approved	O
plans	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
wall	O
equipped	O
with	O
electronic	O
detection	O
devices	O
along	O
the	O
560-mile	O
border	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
to	O
deter	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Last	O
week	O
Afghan	B-MISC
Television	O
reported	O
that	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
interim	O
administration	O
has	O
banned	O
cultivation	O
of	O
opium	O
poppies	O
in	O
an	O
attempt	O
to	O
end	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Opium	O
is	O
the	O
raw	O
ingredient	O
for	O
heroin	O
.	O

The	O
now-ousted	O
Taliban	B-ORG
militia	O
in	O
July	O
2000	O
also	O
banned	O
production	O
of	O
opium	O
.	O

The	O
ban	O
was	O
strictly	O
enforced	O
and	O
resulted	O
in	O
a	O
decrease	O
in	O
opium	O
production	O
from	O
3200	O
tons	O
to	O
185	O
tons	O
.	O

Desperate	O
Afghan	B-MISC
farmers	O
resumed	O
growing	O
opium	O
poppies	O
soon	O
after	O
the	O
hard-line	O
militia	O
lost	O
power	O
in	O
December	O
2001	O
.	O

Iranian	B-MISC
law	O
applies	O
the	O
death	O
penalty	O
for	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
past	O
20	O
years	O
more	O
than	O
3000	O
police	O
officers	O
have	O
been	O
killed	O
in	O
anti-drug	O
raids	O
.	O

2001-12-20	O

Canada	B-LOC
(	O
CA	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
terrorism	O

Canadian	B-MISC
government	O
's	O
warning	O
of	O
al-Qaeda	O
's	O
capability	O
to	O
launch	O
a	O
cyberattack	O
causes	O
various	O
industries	O
to	O
review	O
their	O
preparedness	O
.	O

Critical	O
infrastructures	O
including	O
energy	O
and	O
transportation	O
providers	O
cite	O
close	O
work	O
with	O
Government	O
to	O
remain	O
aware	O
of	O
threats	O
and	O
to	O
update	O
accordingly	O
.	O

A	O
recent	O
government	O
warning	O
that	O
al-Qaeda	O
terrorists	O
could	O
launch	O
a	O
cyberattack	O
on	O
Canadian	B-MISC
interests	O
or	O
critical	O
infrastructure	O
has	O
caused	O
many	O
concerned	O
industries	O
to	O
review	O
their	O
security	O
systems	O
.	O

Vice	O
President	O
of	O
Canadian	B-MISC
electricity	O
Association	B-ORG
Francis	B-PER
Bradley	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
company	O
has	O
a	O
warning	O
system	O
for	O
both	O
physical	O
and	O
cyberattacks	O
.	O

Bradley	B-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
company	O
has	O
been	O
significantly	O
focused	O
on	O
prevention	O
of	O
cyberattacks	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
recent	O
interview	O
Bradley	B-PER
stated	O
that	O
many	O
utility	O
firms	O
perform	O
a	O
brief	O
review	O
of	O
their	O
multi-tiered	O
response	O
systems	O
after	O
such	O
warnings	O
are	O
issued	O
.	O

The	O
warning	O
from	O
the	O
Canadian	B-MISC
Department	O
of	O
National	I-ORG
Defense	I-ORG
's	O
office	O
of	O
critical	O
infrastructure	O
protection	O
and	O
emergency	O
service	O
was	O
quietly	O
released	O
on	O
20	O
December	O
2001	O
and	O
cited	O
no	O
specific	O
threat	O
.	O

Director	O
of	O
threat	O
analysis	O
at	O
the	O
Canadian	B-MISC
Department	O
of	O
National	I-ORG
Defense	I-ORG
's	O
office	O
of	O
critical	O
infrastructure	O
protection	O
and	O
emergency	O
service	O
Brenda	B-PER
hensler-Hobbs	O
stated	O
that	O
following	O
the	O
attacks	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
2001	O
the	O
Canadian	B-MISC
Government	O
specifically	O
examined	O
the	O
potential	O
cyber-capability	O
of	O
al-Qaeda	O
and	O
Osama	B-PER
bin	I-PER
Laden	I-PER
's	O
followers	O
.	O

Hensler-Hobbs	B-MISC
stated	O
that	O
the	O
Canadian	B-MISC
government	O
has	O
no	O
knowledge	O
of	O
Al-Qaeda	B-ORG
having	O
engaged	O
in	O
cyberattacks	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
but	O
that	O
leader	O
bin	B-PER
Laden	I-PER
has	O
suggested	O
that	O
if	O
he	O
chose	O
to	O
launch	O
cyberattacks	O
he	O
could	O
have	O
the	O
means	O
available	O
to	O
him	O
.	O

In	O
summary	O
of	O
the	O
recent	O
warning	O
stating	O
that	O
such	O
an	O
attack	O
could	O
be	O
executed	O
in	O
the	O
very	O
near	O
future	O
hensler-Hobbs	O
stated	O
that	O
bin	O
Laden	B-PER
's	O
location	O
was	O
irrelevant	O
because	O
bin	O
Laden	B-PER
possesses	O
the	O
money	O
and	O
supporters	O
necessary	O
to	O
have	O
such	O
an	O
attack	O
executed	O
by	O
others	O
.	O

A	O
number	O
of	O
al-Qaeda	O
militants	O
including	O
Millennium	O
plot	O
bomber	O
Ahmed	B-PER
Ressam	I-PER
are	O
known	O
to	O
have	O
remained	O
in	O
Canada	B-LOC
.	O

Many	O
are	O
located	O
in	O
Montreal	B-LOC
.	O

Hensler-Hobbs	B-MISC
stated	O
that	O
the	O
proliferation	O
and	O
availability	O
of	O
Hacker	O
tools	O
and	O
the	O
low	O
skill	O
level	O
needed	O
to	O
conduct	O
cyberattacks	O
demonstrate	O
the	O
ease	O
of	O
launching	O
an	O
attack	O
anywhere	O
.	O

Hensler-Hobbs	B-MISC
cited	O
the	O
example	O
of	O
the	O
Montreal-based	B-MISC
Hacker	O
known	O
as	O
mafiaboy	O
who	O
attacked	O
U.S.	B-LOC
websites	O
including	O
Amazon.com	B-ORG
in	O
2000	O
.	O

Many	O
think	O
that	O
security	O
must	O
be	O
improved	O
at	O
North	B-MISC
American	I-MISC
critical	O
infrastructures	O
including	O
energy	O
and	O
transportation	O
providers	O
and	O
the	O
financial	O
services	O
sector	O
that	O
are	O
largely	O
interconnected	O
.	O

Many	O
businesses	O
began	O
preparing	O
for	O
cyber	O
incidents	O
before	O
the	O
year	O
2000	O
.	O

A	O
separate	O
report	O
issued	O
recently	O
by	O
the	O
U.S.	B-LOC
government-funded	O
research	O
group	O
computer	O
science	O
and	O
telecommunications	O
Board	O
stated	O
that	O
cyber	O
security	O
needs	O
considerable	O
improvement	O
.	O

For	O
example	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
a	O
Canadian	B-MISC
government	O
estimate	O
the	O
love	O
bug	O
launched	O
in	O
May	O
2000	O
caused	O
6.7	O
billion	O
U.S.	B-LOC
dollars	O
in	O
damage	O
and	O
disrupted	O
Canadian	B-MISC
government	O
systems	O
.	O

Bell	B-ORG
Canada	I-ORG
spokesman	O
Andrew	B-PER
Cole	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Bell	B-ORG
Canada	I-ORG
is	O
prepared	O
and	O
remains	O
prepared	O
for	O
various	O
potential	O
situations	O
and	O
scenarios	O
.	O

Cole	B-PER
stated	O
--	O

Bell	B-ORG
Canada	I-ORG
works	O
very	O
closely	O
with	O
the	O
Government	O
and	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
to	O
be	O
aware	O
of	O
security	O
concerns	O
and	O
to	O
update	O
accordingly	O
.	O

Bell	B-ORG
Canada	I-ORG
worked	O
closely	O
with	O
U.S.	B-LOC
officials	O
and	O
firms	O
after	O
the	O
attacks	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
2001	O
.	O

Bell	B-ORG
Canada	I-ORG
provides	O
a	O
total	O
of	O
26	O
million	O
phone	O
and	O
Internet	B-MISC
connections	O
to	O
a	O
nation	O
of	O
30	O
million	O
people	O
.	O

Bradley	B-PER
stated	O
--	O

Electricity	O
firms	O
have	O
strong	O
warning	O
systems	O
that	O
are	O
coordinated	O
by	O
the	O
North	B-MISC
American	I-MISC
Electric	O
reliability	O
Council	O
.	O

There	O
has	O
not	O
been	O
a	O
cyber	O
event	O
that	O
has	O
resulted	O
in	O
a	O
loss	O
of	O
power	O
for	O
utility	O
customers	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
little	O
possibility	O
that	O
a	O
cyberattack	O
would	O
disable	O
a	O
North	B-MISC
American	I-MISC
electric	O
grid	O
.	O

Electric	O
companies	O
are	O
well	O
prepared	O
and	O
are	O
making	O
all	O
preparations	O
required	O
to	O
be	O
ready	O
for	O
any	O
physical	O
or	O
cyberattack	O
.	O

The	O
North	B-MISC
American	I-MISC
Electric	O
reliability	O
Council	O
's	O
30	O
largest	O
utility	O
companies	O
went	O
on	O
their	O
highest	O
alert	O
on	O
September	O
11	O
and	O
many	O
still	O
have	O
an	O
increased	O
security	O
presence	O
in	O
effect	O
and	O
plan	O
to	O
extend	O
it	O
further	O
.	O

2002-01-26	O

Russia	B-LOC
(	O
RU	B-MISC
)	O

International	O
;	O
space	O
;	O
energy	O

Russia	B-LOC
's	O
military	O
authorities	O
criticized	O
Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
Power	B-ORG
Company	I-ORG
for	O
imposing	O
a	O
shutdown	O
on	O
supplies	O
to	O
a	O
command	O
center	O
that	O
guides	O
military	O
satellites	O
in	O
orbit	O
and	O
contributes	O
to	O
systems	O
controlling	O
the	O
international	O
space	O
station	O
.	O

The	O
Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
company	O
disconnected	O
a	O
major	O
control	O
center	O
of	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
space	O
forces	O
located	O
in	O
Kamchatka	B-LOC
early	O
Saturday	O
,	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
Space	O
Forces	O
press	O
service	O
said	O
.	O

Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
feeds	O
power	O
to	O
the	O
vast	O
Kamchatka	B-LOC
peninsula	O
in	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
far	O
east	O
.	O

A	O
statement	O
from	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
Space	O
Forces	O
press	O
services	O
on	O
020126	O
called	O
the	O
action	O
a	O
direct	O
violation	O
of	O
government	O
decrees	O
on	O
defense	O
facilities	O
and	O
stated	O
that	O
it	O
could	O
have	O
led	O
to	O
the	O
loss	O
of	O
a	O
spacecraft	O
costing	O
hundreds	O
of	O
millions	O
of	O
rubles	O
.	O

The	O
monitoring	O
center	O
is	O
a	O
key	O
element	O
in	O
maintaining	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
satellite	O
network	O
in	O
orbit	O
and	O
plays	O
a	O
part	O
in	O
operations	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
space	O
platform	O
Alfa	B-ORG
.	O

Officials	O
at	O
the	O
command	O
center	O
took	O
urgent	O
measures	O
to	O
use	O
reserve	O
power	O
units	O
to	O
keep	O
the	O
system	O
functioning	O
and	O
to	O
temporarily	O
provide	O
residential	O
centers	O
with	O
electricity	O
.	O

Several	O
other	O
military	O
bases	O
and	O
strategic	O
defense	O
units	O
were	O
affected	O
.	O

The	O
State	O
power	O
monopoly	O
United	O
energy	O
services	O
and	O
its	O
regional	O
subsidiary	O
Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
launched	O
a	O
program	O
of	O
power	O
cuts	O
to	O
long-term	O
debtors	O
on	O
020125	O
.	O

United	O
energy	O
services	O
argues	O
that	O
non-payment	O
of	O
bills	O
has	O
prevented	O
it	O
from	O
maintaining	O
supplies	O
.	O

The	O
Russian	B-MISC
Space	O
Forces	O
,	O
the	O
space	O
branch	O
of	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
armed	O
forces	O
,	O
expressed	O
alarm	O
at	O
the	O
prospect	O
of	O
further	O
power	O
cuts	O
resulting	O
from	O
delays	O
in	O
Federal	O
budget	O
resources	O
reaching	O
local	O
authorities	O
on	O
time	O
.	O

2002-01-28	O

Russian	B-LOC
Federation	I-LOC
(	O
RU	B-MISC
)	O

International	O
;	O
space	O
;	O
energy	O

Russian	B-MISC
space	O
officials	O
warn	O
that	O
power	O
cuts	O
against	O
the	O
military	O
for	O
non-payment	O
of	O
bills	O
,	O
like	O
the	O
one	O
at	O
a	O
command	O
center	O
in	O
the	O
Far	B-LOC
East	I-LOC
Kamchatka	I-LOC
Peninsula	I-LOC
of	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
Space	O
Forces	O
,	O
could	O
have	O
catastrophic	O
consequences	O
.	O

28	O
January	O
2002	O
--	O
Russian	B-MISC
space	O
officials	O
warned	O
that	O
power	O
cuts	O
against	O
the	O
military	O
for	O
non-payment	O
of	O
bills	O
could	O
have	O
catastrophic	O
consequences	O
.	O

Russian	B-MISC
space	O
agency	O
spokesman	O
Sergei	B-PER
Gorbunov	I-PER
announced	O
--	O

A	O
weekend	O
black-out	O
at	O
a	O
command	O
center	O
in	O
the	O
Far	B-LOC
East	I-LOC
Kamchatka	I-LOC
Peninsula	I-LOC
of	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
space	O
forces	O
had	O
not	O
affected	O
the	O
international	O
space	O
station	O
(	O
ISS	B-ORG
)	O
.	O

The	O
Kamchatka	B-ORG
Command	I-ORG
Center	I-ORG
maintains	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
satellite	O
network	O
in	O
orbit	O
.	O

The	O
Kamchatka	B-LOC
command	O
center	O
plays	O
a	O
role	O
in	O
ISS	B-ORG
operations	O
.	O

cutting	O
power	O
to	O
command	O
centers	O
could	O
pose	O
dangers	O
for	O
Russian	B-MISC
space	O
installations	O
.	O

Power	O
cuts	O
could	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
failure	O
of	O
all	O
work	O
with	O
space	O
craft	O
.	O

The	O
ISS	B-ORG
could	O
function	O
for	O
an	O
orbit	O
or	O
two	O
without	O
ground	O
control	O
by	O
using	O
standby	O
systems	O
.	O

A	O
total	O
unexpected	O
loss	O
of	O
power	O
during	O
control	O
of	O
military	O
equipment	O
could	O
be	O
catastrophic	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
or	O
UES	B-ORG
or	O
the	O
Ministry	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Defense	I-ORG
must	O
resolve	O
the	O
issue	O
.	O

The	O
Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
company	O
feeds	O
power	O
to	O
Kamchatka	B-LOC
Peninsula	I-LOC
.	O

On	O
26	O
January	O
2002	O
Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
disconnected	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
Space	O
Forces	O
center	O
for	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

Kamchatenergo	B-PER
is	O
1	O
of	O
several	O
regional	O
subsidiaries	O
of	O
State	O
power	O
monopoly	O
United	O
energy	O
services	O
(	O
UES	B-ORG
)	O
.	O

On	O
25	O
January	O
2002	O
UES	B-ORG
cut	O
power	O
to	O
long-term	O
debtors	O
.	O

Kamchatenergo	B-MISC
stated	O
that	O
non-payment	O
of	O
bills	O
prevent	O
it	O
from	O
maintaining	O
power	O
supplies	O
.	O

The	O
ISS	B-ORG
--	O

consists	O
of	O
16	O
nations	O

is	O
hailed	O
as	O
an	O
example	O
of	O
international	O
cooperation	O
in	O
space	O

has	O
been	O
largely	O
built	O
by	O
Russia	B-LOC
.	O

Russia	B-LOC
provided	O
several	O
ISS	B-ORG
modules	O
including	O
Zvezda	B-MISC
and	O
Zarya	B-PER

Several	O
other	O
military	O
bases	O
including	O
some	O
strategic	O
defense	O
units	O
were	O
affected	O
by	O
the	O
power	O
outage	O
.	O

Russian	B-MISC
space	O
forces	O
is	O
the	O
space	O
branch	O
of	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
armed	O
forces	O
.	O

ISS	B-ORG
module	O
unity	O
was	O
built	O
by	O
the	O
US	B-LOC
.	O

2002-02-01	O

Narcotics	O
;	O
crime	O
;	O
international	O

An	O
Australian	B-MISC
jury	O
found	O
that	O
an	O
Uzbekistan	B-LOC
Olympic	B-MISC
boxing	O
official	O
was	O
defamed	O
in	O
a	O
book	O
about	O
alleged	O
Olympic	B-MISC
corruption	O
in	O
which	O
he	O
was	O
depicted	O
as	O
a	O
major	O
international	O
heroin	O
dealer	O
and	O
racketeer	O
.	O

A	O
New	B-LOC
South	B-LOC
Wales	I-LOC
Supreme	O
Court	O
jury	O
took	O
just	O
over	O
2	O
hours	O
on	O
020201	O
to	O
find	O
Gafur	B-PER
Rakhimov	I-PER
had	O
been	O
libelled	O
in	O
a	O
book	O
the	O
Great	O
Olympic	B-MISC
swindle	O
which	O
alleges	O
Olympic	B-MISC
corruption	O
.	O

Gafur	B-PER
Rakhimov	I-PER
is	O
an	O
Uzbekistan	B-LOC
Olympic	B-MISC
boxing	O
official	O
and	O
was	O
depicted	O
in	O
the	O
book	O
as	O
a	O
major	O
international	O
heroin	O
dealer	O
and	O
racketeer	O
.	O

The	O
Great	O
Olympic	B-MISC
swindle	O
was	O
written	O
by	O
British	B-MISC
journalist	O
Andrew	B-PER
Jennings	I-PER
and	O
published	O
by	O
Simon	B-PER
and	O
Schuster	O
.	O

The	O
Rakhimov	B-PER
case	O
will	O
now	O
go	O
to	O
a	O
single	O
judge	O
to	O
hear	O
defences	O
and	O
decide	O
any	O
damages	O
to	O
be	O
awarded	O
to	O
Rakhimov	B-PER
.	O

The	O
Great	O
Olympic	B-MISC
swindle	O
implied	O
that	O
Gafur	B-PER
Rakhimov	I-PER
had	O
been	O
engaged	O
in	O
fraud	O
,	O
prostitution	O
,	O
assassination	O
,	O
gun	O
running	O
and	O
plutonium	O
smuggling	O
.	O

The	O
book	O
also	O
implied	O
that	O
the	O
businessman	O
was	O
a	O
gangster	O
in	O
the	O
Soviet	B-MISC
black	O
economy	O
and	O
had	O
traded	O
sporting	O
medals	O
for	O
bribes	O
.	O

Rakhimov	B-PER
was	O
Vice-President	O
of	O
the	O
Olympic	B-ORG
Council	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Asia	I-ORG
and	O
an	O
Executive	O
Member	O
of	O
the	O
International	B-ORG
Amateur	I-ORG
Boxing	I-ORG
Association	I-ORG
.	O

Rakhimov	B-PER
was	O
also	O
said	O
to	O
have	O
bribed	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
International	B-ORG
Amateur	I-ORG
Boxing	I-ORG
Federation	I-ORG
in	O
the	O
vote	O
for	O
the	O
Federation	B-ORG
Presidency	I-ORG
.	O

Jennings	B-PER
is	O
a	O
long-time	O
critic	O
of	O
the	O
International	B-ORG
Olympic	I-ORG
Committee	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
020201	O
verdict	O
followed	O
2	O
defamation	O
actions	O
brought	O
last	O
year	O
by	O
Rakhimov	B-PER
against	O
the	O
Australian	B-ORG
Broadcasting	I-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
(	O
ABC	B-ORG
)	O
and	O
Jennings	B-PER
and	O
against	O
the	O
Sydney	B-ORG
Morning	I-ORG
Herald	I-ORG
(	O
SMH	B-ORG
)	O
and	O
Jennings	B-PER
.	O

A	O
jury	O
found	O
in	O
the	O
case	O
involving	O
the	O
ABC	B-ORG
that	O
ABC	B-ORG
's	O
flagship	O
current	O
affairs	O
program	O
four	O
corners	O
had	O
implied	O
Rakhimov	B-PER
knew	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
most	O
dangerous	O
criminals	O
and	O
was	O
suspected	O
by	O
the	O
FBI	B-ORG
of	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

That	O
Panel	O
found	O
those	O
insinuations	O
were	O
not	O
defamatory	O
and	O
threw	O
out	O
the	O
case	O
against	O
the	O
ABC	B-ORG
and	O
Jennings	B-PER
.	O

The	O
SMH	B-ORG
and	O
Jennings	B-PER
were	O
then	O
sued	O
over	O
3	O
articles	O
published	O
in	O
the	O
lead-up	O
to	O
the	O
000000	O
Olympics	B-MISC
.	O

The	O
jury	O
in	O
that	O
case	O
found	O
Rakhimov	B-PER
had	O
been	O
painted	O
as	O
a	O
major	O
international	O
criminal	O
and	O
had	O
been	O
defamed	O
.	O

2002-02-10	O

Tajikistan	B-LOC
(	O
TJ	B-LOC
)	O
;	O
Uzbekistan	B-LOC
(	O
UZ	B-LOC
)	O
;	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
(	O
AF	O
)	O
;	O
Kyrgyzstan	B-LOC
(	O
KG	O
)	O
;	O
Kazakhstan	B-LOC
(	O
KZ	B-LOC
)	O
;	O
Turkmenistan	B-LOC
(	O
TM	B-ORG
)	O

International	O
;	O
narcotics	O
;	O
terrorism	O
;	O
politics	O

OSCE	B-ORG
urges	O
permanent	O
end	O
to	O
Afghan	B-MISC
terrorism	O
and	O
drug-trafficking	O
to	O
create	O
long-term	O
stability	O
in	O
Central	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

Expert	O
states	O
that	O
cultivation	O
of	O
opium	O
and	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
are	O
deeply	O
entrenched	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
will	O
be	O
impossible	O
to	O
eradicate	O
.	O

The	O
OSCE	B-ORG
envoy	O
in	O
neighboring	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
Marc	B-PER
Gilbert	I-PER
stated	O
to	O
the	O
government	O
weekly	O
national	O
gazette	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
now	O
hopes	O
that	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
will	O
develop	O
its	O
democratic	O
institutions	O
and	O
end	O
terrorism	O
and	O
drug-smuggling	O
resulting	O
in	O
greater	O
stability	O
in	O
Central	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O

Gilbert	B-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
post-Soviet	O
republics	O
in	O
central	O
Asia	I-LOC
fought	O
terrorism	O
by	O
giving	O
material	O
and	O
other	O
necessary	O
help	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
anti-terrorist	O
coalition	O
in	O
the	O
war	O
against	O
Saudi	B-MISC
dissident	O
Osama	B-PER
bin	I-PER
Laden	I-PER
and	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
regime	O
.	O

Both	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
and	O
Uzbekistan	B-LOC
share	O
a	O
border	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
and	O
have	O
experienced	O
raids	O
by	O
Taliban-backed	O
Islamic	B-MISC
militants	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
.	O

Neighboring	O
Kyrgyzstan	B-LOC
has	O
also	O
experienced	O
raids	O
by	O
Taliban-backed	O
Islamic	B-MISC
militants	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
.	O

Kazakhstan	B-LOC
also	O
became	O
a	O
key	O
U.S.	B-LOC
partner	O
in	O
the	O
Afghan	B-MISC
war	O
opening	O
its	O
airspace	O
to	O
military	O
overflights	O
.	O

Turkmenistan	B-LOC
maintained	O
a	O
more	O
neutral	O
stance	O
.	O

Turkmenistan	B-LOC
borders	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Gilbert	B-PER
stated	O
that	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
's	O
positive	O
and	O
responsible	O
approach	O
to	O
the	O
crisis	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
has	O
significantly	O
improved	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
image	O
internationally	O
.	O

Tajik	B-MISC
government	O
expert	O
and	O
head	O
of	O
the	O
Tajik	B-ORG
Drug	I-ORG
Control	I-ORG
Agency	I-ORG
Vladimir	B-PER
Rakhmonov	I-PER
stated	O
on	O
10	O
February	O
2002	O
that	O
the	O
U.S.-led	B-MISC
war	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
had	O
failed	O
to	O
stop	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
across	O
the	O
border	O
into	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
.	O

Rakhmonov	B-PER
stated	O
to	O
Interfax	B-ORG
--	O

Opium	O
and	O
heroin	O
are	O
a	O
form	O
of	O
hard-currency	O
reserve	O
for	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Drug	O
trafficking	O
from	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
has	O
been	O
concealed	O
so	O
securely	O
that	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
impossible	O
to	O
uncover	O
.	O

Drug	O
trafficking	O
from	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
resumed	O
during	O
a	O
brief	O
hiatus	O
in	O
the	O
anti-terrorist	O
operation	O
.	O

In	O
2001	O
Tajik	B-MISC
law-enforcement	O
agencies	O
and	O
Russian	B-MISC
border	O
guards	O
seized	O
8.8	O
tons	O
of	O
drugs	O
including	O
4.2	O
tons	O
of	O
heroin	O
.	O

This	O
represented	O
a	O
26	O
percent	O
increase	O
overall	O
in	O
2001	O
with	O
3	O
times	O
the	O
amount	O
of	O
heroin	O
.	O

Many	O
years	O
would	O
be	O
needed	O
to	O
convert	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
agriculture	O
historically	O
specialized	O
in	O
the	O
growing	O
of	O
raw	O
opium	O
.	O

Cultivation	O
of	O
raw	O
opium	O
provided	O
the	O
only	O
source	O
of	O
income	O
for	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
rural	O
population	O
.	O

Tajikistan	B-LOC
's	O
780-mile	O
border	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
is	O
patrolled	O
by	O
approximately	O
11000	O
Russian	B-MISC
soldiers	O
under	O
a	O
1992	O
agreement	O
between	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
and	O
Tajik	B-MISC
Governments	O
.	O

2002-03-01	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
(	O
AF	O
)	O
;	O
Russian	B-LOC
Federation	I-LOC
(	O
RU	B-MISC
)	O

International	O
;	O
narcotics	O
;	O
terrorism	O

Afghan	B-MISC
officials	O
conducted	O
talks	O
with	O
Russian	B-MISC
officials	O
asking	O
for	O
assistance	O
in	O
stopping	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
large	O
illegal	O
opium	O
and	O
heroin	O
trade	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
seeks	O
to	O
end	O
poppy	O
harvesting	O
and	O
increase	O
border	O
control	O
.	O

March	O
1	O
,	O
2002	O
interim	O
interior	O
minister	O
of	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
Yunus	B-PER
Qanooni	I-PER
asked	O
Russian	B-MISC
officials	O
to	O
assist	O
in	O
combating	O
the	O
drugs	O
trade	O
and	O
establishing	O
security	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Qanooni	B-PER
is	O
a	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
Northern	B-LOC
Alliance	I-LOC
.	O

Qanooni	B-PER
told	O
Russian	B-MISC
Deputy	O
Minister	O
for	O
Emergency	O
Situations	O
Yury	B-PER
Vorobyov	I-PER
--	O

Unfortunately	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
six	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
rule	O
of	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
turned	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
into	O
a	O
center	O
of	O
terrorism	O
and	O
drugs	O
.	O

The	O
struggle	O
against	O
terrorism	O
and	O
against	O
drugs	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
security	O
is	O
a	O
priority	O
for	O
the	O
Administration	O
of	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

But	O
combating	O
terrorism	O
and	O
drugs	O
requires	O
joint	O
efforts	O
.	O

Peace	O
and	O
stability	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
is	O
not	O
only	O
in	O
the	O
interests	O
of	O
the	O
Afghani	O
people	O
and	O
nation	O
but	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
interim	O
government	O
stated	O
that	O
it	O
would	O
take	O
firm	O
measures	O
very	O
quickly	O
to	O
prevent	O
the	O
harvest	O
of	O
poppy	O
in	O
the	O
wake	O
of	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
regime	O
's	O
fall	O
late	O
last	O
year	O
.	O

Leader	O
of	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
interim	O
government	O
Hamid	B-PER
Karzai	I-PER
said	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
poppy	O
harvesting	O
and	O
the	O
lucrative	O
trafficking	O
of	O
opium	O
and	O
heroin	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
top	O
priority	O
.	O

The	O
anti-drug	O
effort	O
is	O
strongly	O
supported	O
by	O
Western	B-MISC
countries	O
,	O
whose	O
populations	O
are	O
a	O
major	O
market	O
for	O
heroin	O
and	O
opium	O
from	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

February	O
28	O
,	O
2002	O
Kabul	B-LOC
officials	O
announced	O
that	O
Afghan	B-MISC
police	O
are	O
creating	O
their	O
first	O
anti-narcotics	O
units	O
with	O
the	O
help	O
of	O
the	O
United	B-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
due	O
to	O
concern	O
that	O
the	O
country	O
could	O
again	O
become	O
a	O
major	O
producer	O
of	O
opium	O
.	O

February	O
28	O
,	O
2002	O
Qanooni	B-PER
stated	O
in	O
talks	O
with	O
Russian	B-MISC
Interior	O
Minister	O
Boris	B-PER
Gryzlov	I-PER
that	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
main	O
task	O
is	O
to	O
prevent	O
future	O
drugs	O
production	O
.	O

Qanooni	B-PER
outlined	O
a	O
three-stage	O
plan	O
of	O
action	O
--	O

Afghan	B-MISC
authorities	O
will	O
seek	O
to	O
ban	O
poppy	O
harvesting	O
.	O

Afghan	B-MISC
authorities	O
will	O
strengthen	O
the	O
borders	O
around	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Afghan	B-MISC
authorities	O
will	O
cooperate	O
with	O
the	O
security	O
forces	O
of	O
neighboring	O
states	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
is	O
thought	O
to	O
be	O
responsible	O
for	O
75	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
opium	O
and	O
80	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
heroin	O
traded	O
illegally	O
in	O
Europe	B-LOC
.	O

Approximately	O
11000	O
Russian	B-MISC
guards	O
patrol	O
the	O
1200-kilometre	O
(	O
750-mile	O
)	O
border	O
between	O
Russia	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
under	O
a	O
1992	O
agreement	O
signed	O
by	O
Moscow	B-LOC
and	O
Dushanbe	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
Northern	B-LOC
Alliance	I-LOC
opposes	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
but	O
tolerated	O
the	O
harvest	O
of	O
poppy	O
in	O
territory	O
it	O
controlled	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
interim	O
government	O
has	O
been	O
in	O
power	O
for	O
2	O
months	O
.	O

2002-03-04	O

International	O
;	O
Government	O
;	O
military	O

South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
defense	O
ministry	O
under	O
attack	O
in	O
parliament	O
over	O
allegations	O
it	O
is	O
favoring	O
U.S.	B-LOC
company	O
Boeing	B-ORG
for	O
multi-billion-dollar	O
fighter	O
project	O
.	O

Newspaper	O
reports	O
reveal	O
that	O
French-made	O
plane	O
was	O
rated	O
higher	O
in	O
air	O
force	O
evaluations	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
Government	O
is	O
instead	O
responding	O
to	O
political	O
pressure	O
from	O
the	O
U.S.	B-LOC
and	O
Boeing	B-ORG
.	O

South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
Defense	B-ORG
Ministry	I-ORG
came	O
under	O
attack	O
in	O
Parliament	O
on	O
04	O
March	O
2002	O
over	O
allegations	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
favoring	O
U.S.	B-LOC
company	O
Boeing	B-ORG
for	O
a	O
multi-billion-dollar	O
fighter	O
project	O
.	O

Ruling	O
and	O
opposition	O
lawmakers	O
criticized	O
the	O
Ministry	O
as	O
newspapers	O
reported	O
that	O
the	O
French-made	B-MISC
fighter	O
Rafale	B-MISC
had	O
scored	O
the	O
highest	O
marks	O
of	O
any	O
of	O
the	O
4	O
contenders	O
in	O
field	O
tests	O
performed	O
by	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
Air	B-ORG
Force	I-ORG
evaluators	O
.	O

The	O
3.2	O
billion	O
U.S.	B-LOC
dollar	O
project	O
to	O
buy	O
40	O
fighters	O
will	O
be	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
international	O
military	O
contracts	O
awarded	O
this	O
year	O
but	O
it	O
has	O
encountered	O
multiple	O
obstacles	O
.	O

Award	O
of	O
the	O
contract	O
was	O
temporarily	O
suspended	O
in	O
February	O
2002	O
after	O
the	O
prices	O
offered	O
by	O
4	O
bidders	O
were	O
judged	O
too	O
high	O
.	O

South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
defense	O
ministry	O
promised	O
to	O
conclude	O
its	O
first-stage	O
appraisal	O
by	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
March	O
2002	O
.	O

There	O
has	O
also	O
been	O
much	O
newspaper	O
speculation	O
that	O
the	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
government	O
might	O
yield	O
to	O
U.S.	B-LOC
pressure	O
to	O
buy	O
Boeing	B-ORG
's	O
aged	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
.	O

Speculation	O
grew	O
in	O
February	O
2002	O
when	O
Defense	O
Minister	O
Kim	B-PER
Dong-Shin	I-PER
stressed	O
that	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
should	O
consider	O
security	O
ties	O
with	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
in	O
the	O
project	O
.	O

The	O
other	O
competing	O
planes	O
are	O
the	O
Dassault	B-ORG
firm	O
's	O
Rafale	B-MISC
,	O
the	O
Eurofighter	B-ORG
Consortium	I-ORG
's	O
typhoon	O
2000	O
and	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
Su-32	B-ORG
made	O
by	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
.	O

Dassault	B-ORG
is	O
seeking	O
its	O
first	O
foreign	O
order	O
for	O
the	O
Rafale	B-MISC
.	O

Kang	B-PER
Chang-Sung	I-PER
of	O
the	O
opposition	O
Grand	B-ORG
National	I-ORG
Party	I-ORG
expressed	O
doubt	O
of	O
the	O
fairness	O
of	O
the	O
evaluation	O
methods	O
stating	O
that	O
his	O
party	O
suspects	O
that	O
the	O
Defense	B-ORG
Ministry	I-ORG
has	O
political	O
reasons	O
to	O
select	O
the	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
.	O

The	O
ruling	O
Millennium	B-ORG
Democratic	I-ORG
Party	I-ORG
also	O
accused	O
the	O
Ministry	O
of	O
favoring	O
the	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
despite	O
the	O
defense	O
chief	O
's	O
insistence	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
favoritism	O
toward	O
Boeing	B-ORG
.	O

Kim	B-PER
stated	O
--	O

There	O
has	O
been	O
no	O
pressure	O
from	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
.	O

There	O
would	O
be	O
an	O
investigation	O
into	O
how	O
classified	O
documents	O
had	O
been	O
leaked	O
.	O

The	O
Defense	B-ORG
Ministry	I-ORG
was	O
further	O
pressured	O
by	O
numerous	O
newspaper	O
reports	O
of	O
the	O
Air	B-ORG
Force	I-ORG
's	O
evaluation	O
of	O
the	O
Rafale	B-MISC
as	O
excellent	O
in	O
all	O
categories	O
.	O

Newspapers	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
was	O
rated	O
excellent	O
in	O
reliability	O
and	O
support	O
combat	O
capability	O
but	O
met	O
only	O
30	O
percent	O
of	O
core	O
technology	O
requirements	O
.	O

Newspapers	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
Eurofighter	B-ORG
was	O
rated	O
excellent	O
in	O
general	O
function	O
and	O
reliability	O
categories	O
but	O
the	O
Rafale	B-MISC
also	O
earned	O
the	O
excellent	O
rating	O
for	O
its	O
weapons	O
and	O
electronic	O
warfare	O
capability	O
.	O

The	O
Su-35	B-MISC
placed	O
fourth	O
with	O
ratings	O
of	O
ordinary	O
in	O
all	O
five	O
categories	O
.	O

Rafale	B-MISC
reportedly	O
offered	O
more	O
generous	O
terms	O
for	O
technology	O
transfer	O
and	O
subcontracts	O
for	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
aerospace	O
industry	O
.	O

The	O
Ministry	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
air	O
force	O
was	O
just	O
1	O
of	O
4	O
evaluations	O
.	O

Some	O
analysts	O
have	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
study	O
method	O
is	O
biased	O
toward	O
Boeing	B-ORG
noting	O
that	O
the	O
evaluation	O
was	O
revised	O
in	O
February	O
2002	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
all	O
4	O
bidders	O
would	O
receive	O
an	O
automatic	O
60	O
points	O
for	O
technology	O
transfer	O
.	O

The	O
English-language	B-LOC
Korea	B-ORG
Herald	I-ORG
newspaper	O
stated	O
that	O
this	O
revision	O
gives	O
an	O
advantage	O
to	O
Boeing	B-ORG
which	O
has	O
been	O
reluctant	O
to	O
transfer	O
core	O
technology	O
.	O

The	O
Korea	B-ORG
Herald	I-ORG
stated	O
that	O
when	O
evaluators	O
were	O
conducting	O
their	O
first-stage	O
reports	O
the	O
ministry	O
ordered	O
them	O
to	O
give	O
each	O
bidder	O
grades	O
within	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
60	O
to	O
100	O
points	O
instead	O
of	O
0	O
to	O
100	O
points	O
.	O

The	O
Korea	B-ORG
Herald	I-ORG
stated	O
that	O
critics	O
say	O
Boeing	B-ORG
would	O
benefit	O
most	O
from	O
the	O
points	O
minimum	O
because	O
it	O
would	O
gain	O
fewer	O
points	O
than	O
Dassault	B-ORG
in	O
terms	O
of	O
technology	O
transfer	O
and	O
subcontracts	O
.	O

2002-03-29	O

A	O
senior	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
minister	O
on	O
Friday	O
warned	O
that	O
there	O
could	O
be	O
a	O
new	O
crisis	O
this	O
year	O
over	O
inspections	O
of	O
the	O
rival	O
North	B-LOC
's	O
nuclear	O
program	O
.	O

Senior	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
minister	O
Jeong	B-PER
Se-hyun	I-PER
on	O
020329	O
warned	O
that	O
tensions	O
could	O
rise	O
because	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
wants	O
inspections	O
of	O
its	O
nuclear	O
facilities	O
delayed	O
.	O

Unification	O
Minister	O
Jeong	B-PER
is	O
the	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
government	O
's	O
chief	O
policymaker	O
for	O
relations	O
with	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
.	O

Jeong	B-PER
said	O
in	O
a	O
lecture	O
on	O
South	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
and	O
US	B-LOC
relations	O
with	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
that	O
there	O
was	O
some	O
talk	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
that	O
the	O
nuclear	O
inspection	O
in	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
should	O
be	O
carried	O
out	O
in	O
020800	O
.	O

North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
suggestion	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
inspection	O
should	O
be	O
delayed	O
until	O
050000	O
.	O

Jeong	B-PER
said	O
that	O
a	O
crisis	O
could	O
come	O
in	O
020800	O
on	O
the	O
Korean	B-MISC
peninsula	O
if	O
this	O
issue	O
becomes	O
an	O
international	O
point	O
of	O
contention	O
.	O

Following	O
Jeong	B-PER
's	O
comments	O
another	O
senior	O
government	O
official	O
sought	O
to	O
play	O
down	O
Jeong	B-PER
's	O
remarks	O
about	O
the	O
looming	O
troubles	O
.	O

The	O
unnamed	O
official	O
told	O
the	O
Yonhap	B-ORG
national	O
news	O
agency	O
that	O
talk	O
of	O
pressing	O
for	O
IAEA	B-ORG
inspections	O
in	O
020800	O
had	O
come	O
only	O
from	O
private	O
researchers	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
official	O
said	O
it	O
was	O
speculation	O
that	O
the	O
North	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
government	O
thinks	O
the	O
inspections	O
should	O
be	O
delayed	O
until	O
050000	O
.	O

Top	O
South	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
envoy	O
Lim	B-PER
Won-dong	I-PER
intends	O
to	O
raise	O
international	O
concerns	O
about	O
the	O
North	B-LOC
's	O
nuclear	O
and	O
missile	O
programs	O
when	O
he	O
goes	O
to	O
Pyongyang	B-LOC
020403	O
.	O

Lim	B-PER
is	O
a	O
special	O
advisor	O
to	O
President	O
Kim	B-PER
Dae-jung	I-PER
on	O
national	O
security	O
and	O
foreign	O
affairs	O
.	O

Lim	B-PER
has	O
also	O
warned	O
of	O
a	O
looming	O
nuclear	O
crisis	O
on	O
the	O
Korean	B-MISC
Peninsula	B-ORG
.	O

Military	O
officials	O
said	O
Lim	B-PER
intimated	O
the	O
problems	O
could	O
be	O
as	O
serious	O
as	O
a	O
940000	O
nuclear	O
standoff	O
over	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
suspected	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
development	O
that	O
came	O
close	O
to	O
conflict	O
.	O

The	O
North	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
government	O
agreed	O
to	O
freeze	O
the	O
North	B-MISC
Korean	I-MISC
nuclear	O
program	O
under	O
an	O
accord	O
with	O
a	O
US-led	B-MISC
international	O
consortium	O
.	O

The	O
consortium	O
is	O
to	O
build	O
2	O
light	O
water	O
nuclear	O
reactors	O
that	O
produce	O
less	O
weapons	O
grade	O
fuel	O
than	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
old	O
graphite	O
reactors	O
and	O
provide	O
substitute	O
fuel	O
until	O
they	O
are	O
built	O
.	O

The	O
original	O
030000	O
target	O
date	O
for	O
completion	O
has	O
been	O
put	O
back	O
at	O
least	O
5	O
years	O
because	O
of	O
major	O
political	O
and	O
construction	O
delays	O
.	O

The	O
940000	O
Accord	O
stipulated	O
that	O
the	O
International	B-ORG
Atomic	I-ORG
Energy	I-ORG
Agency	I-ORG
(	O
IAEA	B-ORG
)	O
must	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
inspect	O
North	B-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
's	O
old	O
facilities	O
to	O
see	O
if	O
plutonium	O
has	O
been	O
processed	O
before	O
the	O
core	O
facilities	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
reactors	O
are	O
installed	O
.	O

2002-04-04	O

India	B-LOC
(	O
IN	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
military	O
;	O
business	O

India	B-LOC
's	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
plans	O
to	O
manufacture	O
and	O
maintain	O
140	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
fighter	O
jets	O
for	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
government	O
.	O

India	B-LOC
's	O
State-owned	O
banglalore-based	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
Chairman	O
N.	B-PER
R.	I-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
government	O
has	O
decided	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
will	O
manufacture	O
and	O
maintain	O
140	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jets	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
an	O
agreement	O
had	O
been	O
signed	O
between	O
the	O
Defense	B-ORG
Research	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Organisation	I-ORG
,	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
Air	B-ORG
Force	I-ORG
to	O
upgrade	O
India	B-LOC
's	O
ageing	O
fleet	O
of	O
MiG-27	B-MISC
m	O
aircraft	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
upgrade	O
will	O
be	O
done	O
soon	O
as	O
it	O
has	O
almost	O
been	O
finalised	O
by	O
the	O
Defense	B-ORG
Research	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Organisation	I-ORG
,	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
Air	B-ORG
Force	I-ORG
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
initially	O
40	O
aircraft	O
will	O
be	O
upgraded	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
will	O
receive	O
100	O
percent	O
technology	O
transfer	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jet	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
this	O
technology	O
transfer	O
is	O
good	O
because	O
when	O
an	O
aircraft	O
is	O
sold	O
at	O
a	O
cheap	O
rate	O
you	O
end	O
up	O
paying	O
more	O
when	O
you	O
start	O
maintaining	O
the	O
aircraft	O
and	O
requesting	O
spare	O
aircraft	O
.	O

Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
plans	O
to	O
begin	O
making	O
the	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jet	O
in	O
030000	O
and	O
the	O
first	O
aircraft	O
will	O
be	O
handed	O
over	O
to	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
Air	B-ORG
Force	I-ORG
by	O
040000	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
manufacture	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
140	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jets	O
will	O
be	O
completed	O
by	O
170000	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
will	O
also	O
manufacture	O
the	O
920	O
engines	O
for	O
the	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jets	O
.	O

The	O
initial	O
investment	O
will	O
be	O
650	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
.	O

150	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
of	O
the	O
initial	O
investment	O
will	O
be	O
earmarked	O
for	O
capital	O
investment	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
will	O
fund	O
the	O
initial	O
investment	O
from	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
's	O
own	O
resources	O
and	O
the	O
500	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
needed	O
for	O
tooling	O
,	O
other	O
equipment	O
and	O
technical	O
assistance	O
will	O
be	O
raised	O
when	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
needs	O
it	O
.	O

Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
has	O
paid	O
a	O
licence	O
fee	O
of	O
286	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
to	O
Russia	B-LOC
to	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jets	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
government	O
was	O
also	O
planning	O
to	O
purchase	O
50	O
Sukhoi	B-ORG
30	O
MK	B-MISC
fighter	O
jets	O
from	O
Russia	B-LOC
at	O
a	O
cost	O
of	O
30	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
each	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
's	O
indigenous	O
aircraft	O
will	O
cost	O
slightly	O
less	O
or	O
be	O
almost	O
equal	O
to	O
30	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
each	O
.	O

An	O
earlier	O
340	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollar	O
plan	O
to	O
upgrade	O
India	B-LOC
's	O
MiG-21	B-MISC
fighter	O
jets	O
was	O
delayed	O
by	O
more	O
than	O
5	O
years	O
.	O

Russian	B-MISC
officials	O
blamed	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
Government	O
's	O
intransigence	O
for	O
the	O
delay	O
.	O

The	O
960000	O
Russian	B-MISC
Indian	B-MISC
upgrade	O
deal	O
was	O
meant	O
to	O
be	O
completed	O
within	O
2	O
years	O
but	O
the	O
first	O
2	O
upgraded	O
MiG-21-93	O
jets	O
were	O
not	O
delivered	O
to	O
India	B-LOC
until	O
000000	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
's	O
010000	O
target	O
was	O
to	O
deliver	O
16	O
MiG-21	B-MISC
upgrades	O
but	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
was	O
only	O
able	O
to	O
deliver	O
6	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
had	O
many	O
problems	O
with	O
the	O
French	B-MISC
and	O
Russian	B-MISC
companies	O
and	O
that	O
this	O
year	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
is	O
planning	O
a	O
minimum	O
of	O
24	O
upgrades	O
.	O

N.	B-PER
R.	B-PER
Mohanty	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
had	O
submitted	O
a	O
proposal	O
to	O
the	O
Indian	B-MISC
government	O
for	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
a	O
light	O
attack	O
helicopter	O
and	O
the	O
first	O
flight	O
of	O
India	B-LOC
's	O
intermediate	O
jet	O
trainer	O
hjt-36	O
was	O
planned	O
for	O
020000	O
.	O

Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
stated	O
on	O
020404	O
that	O
Hindustan	B-ORG
Aeronautics	I-ORG
Limited	I-ORG
made	O
a	O
net	O
profit	O
of	O
62	O
million	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
dollars	O
on	O
a	O
sales	O
turnover	O
of	O
27.3	O
billion	O
rupees	O
year-on-year	O
for	O
the	O
fiscal	O
year	O
to	O
020300	O
.	O

2002-04-07	O

Japan	B-LOC
(	O
JP	O
)	O
;	O
China	B-LOC
(	O
CN	B-ORG
)	O

International	O
;	O
politics	O
;	O
Government	O
;	O
weapons	O

Japanese	B-MISC
opposition	O
Liberal	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
chief	O
Ichiro	B-PER
Ozawa	I-PER
announced	O
that	O
Japan	B-LOC
is	O
able	O
to	O
arm	O
itself	O
with	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
overnight	O
if	O
China	B-LOC
proceeds	O
with	O
excessive	O
military	O
build-up	O
.	O

7	O
April	O
2002	O
--	O
Japanese	B-MISC
opposition	O
Liberal	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
chief	O
Ichiro	B-PER
Ozawa	I-PER
has	O
announced	O
that	O
Japan	B-LOC
is	O
able	O
to	O
arm	O
itself	O
with	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
overnight	O
.	O

Japan	B-LOC
will	O
arm	O
itself	O
with	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
if	O
China	B-LOC
proceeds	O
with	O
excessive	O
military	O
expansion	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
discussed	O
Japan	B-LOC
's	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
during	O
a	O
meeting	O
with	O
a	O
Chinese	B-MISC
community	O
party	O
intelligence	O
division	O
official	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
's	O
warning	O
could	O
provoke	O
strong	O
reaction	O
from	O
China	B-LOC
and	O
Asia	B-LOC
.	O

Asia	B-LOC
is	O
on	O
alert	O
to	O
signs	O
of	O
Japan	B-LOC
's	O
military	O
revival	O
.	O

6	O
April	O
2002	O
--	O
in	O
a	O
lecture	O
in	O
the	O
provincial	O
city	O
of	O
Fukuoka	B-PER
Ozawa	I-PER
stated	O
--	O

China	B-LOC
is	O
expanding	O
its	O
military	O
power	O
to	O
attempt	O
to	O
join	O
the	O
ranks	O
of	O
the	O
superpowers	O
.	O

China	B-LOC
is	O
trying	O
to	O
become	O
a	O
military	O
Power	O
like	O
the	O
US	B-LOC
.	O

That	O
Ozawa	B-PER
told	O
an	O
unnamed	O
Chinese	B-MISC
visitor	O
that	O
if	O
China	B-LOC
expands	O
its	O
military	O
power	O
Japanese	B-MISC
people	O
will	O
get	O
hysterical	O
.	O

Japan	B-LOC
can	O
easily	O
produce	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
.	O

Japan	B-LOC
can	O
produce	O
thousands	O
of	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
overnight	O
.	O

Japan	B-LOC
may	O
have	O
enough	O
plutonium	O
at	O
nuclear	O
power	O
plants	O
for	O
3000	O
or	O
4000	O
rounds	O
.	O

If	O
Japan	B-LOC
rises	O
to	O
the	O
occasion	O
Japan	B-LOC
will	O
never	O
be	O
beaten	O
even	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
military	O
power	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
wants	O
a	O
fully	O
democratic	O
China	B-LOC
and	O
a	O
society	O
in	O
which	O
China	B-LOC
and	O
Japan	B-LOC
can	O
coexist	O
.	O

The	O
introduction	O
of	O
democracy	O
to	O
China	B-LOC
is	O
essential	O
to	O
world	O
peace	O
.	O

A	O
breakdown	O
of	O
order	O
in	O
China	B-LOC
will	O
lead	O
to	O
significant	O
global	O
turmoil	O
.	O

A	O
breakdown	O
of	O
order	O
in	O
China	B-LOC
will	O
be	O
worse	O
than	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
or	O
Yugoslavia	B-LOC
.	O

Japanese	B-MISC
newspapers	O
expressed	O
concern	O
about	O
the	O
repercussions	O
of	O
Ozawa	B-PER
's	O
remarks	O
.	O

Conservative	B-ORG
daily	O
newspaper	O
Sankei	B-ORG
Shimbun	I-ORG
stated	O
that	O
Ozawa	B-PER
's	O
nuclear	O
armament	O
threats	O
are	O
an	O
attempt	O
to	O
subdue	O
China	B-LOC
.	O

Sankei	B-ORG
Shimbun	I-ORG
stated	O
that	O
Ozawa	B-PER
's	O
remarks	O
are	O
likely	O
to	O
cause	O
contention	O
in	O
Japan	B-LOC
and	O
abroad	O
.	O

Influential	O
daily	O
newspaper	O
Asahi	B-ORG
Shimbun	I-ORG
anticipates	O
a	O
backlash	O
from	O
the	O
Chinese	B-MISC
government	O
and	O
others	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
is	O
a	O
renowned	O
advocate	O
of	O
a	O
strong	O
armed	O
forces	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
is	O
a	O
conservative	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
is	O
a	O
former	O
secretary	O
general	O
of	O
the	O
ruling	O
Liberal	B-ORG
Democratic	I-ORG
Party	I-ORG
.	O

2002-04-08	O

Japan	B-LOC
(	O
JP	O
)	O

proliferation	O
;	O
politics	O

The	O
Japanese	B-MISC
Government	O
stated	O
on	O
April	O
8	O
,	O
2002	O
its	O
policy	O
of	O
holding	O
no	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
.	O

This	O
was	O
after	O
a	O
senior	O
lawmaker	O
said	O
Japan	B-LOC
can	O
arm	O
itself	O
with	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
overnight	O
.	O

The	O
Japanese	B-MISC
Government	O
stated	O
on	O
April	O
8	O
,	O
2002	O
its	O
policy	O
of	O
holding	O
no	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
.	O

This	O
was	O
after	O
a	O
senior	O
lawmaker	O
said	O
Japan	B-LOC
can	O
arm	O
itself	O
with	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
overnight	O
.	O

Chief	O
Cabinet	O
Secretary	O
Yasuo	B-PER
Fukuda	I-PER
told	O
a	O
press	O
conference	O
that	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
Japan	B-LOC
's	O
policy	O
since	O
World	B-MISC
War	I-MISC
II	I-MISC
to	O
not	O
hold	O
any	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
.	O

Fukuda	B-PER
said	O
that	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
no	O
changes	O
in	O
Japan	B-LOC
adherence	O
to	O
the	O
policy	O
and	O
that	O
Japan	B-LOC
wishes	O
all	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
would	O
disappear	O
from	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

A	O
speech	O
by	O
opposition	O
Liberal	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
chief	O
Ichiro	B-PER
Ozawa	I-PER
told	O
a	O
Chinese	B-MISC
intelligence	O
official	O
that	O
Japanese	B-MISC
people	O
will	O
get	O
hysterical	O
if	O
China	B-LOC
continued	O
to	O
build	O
its	O
military	O
strength	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
said	O
it	O
would	O
be	O
easy	O
for	O
Japan	B-LOC
to	O
produce	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
and	O
that	O
Japan	B-LOC
can	O
produce	O
thousands	O
of	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
overnight	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
stated	O
that	O
Japan	B-LOC
could	O
have	O
enough	O
plutonium	O
at	O
nuclear	O
power	O
plants	O
for	O
3000	O
or	O
4000	O
rounds	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
is	O
a	O
renowned	O
advocate	O
of	O
strong	O
armed	O
forces	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
said	O
that	O
if	O
Japan	B-LOC
rises	O
to	O
the	O
occasion	O
then	O
Japan	B-LOC
will	O
never	O
be	O
beaten	O
even	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
military	O
power	O
.	O

Ozawa	B-PER
wanted	O
a	O
fully	O
democratic	O
China	B-LOC
and	O
an	O
environment	O
in	O
which	O
China	B-LOC
and	O
Japan	B-LOC
can	O
co-exist	O
.	O

Greenpeace	B-ORG
International	O
said	O
Ozawa	B-PER
's	O
comment	O
confirmed	O
the	O
threat	O
posed	O
by	O
Japan	B-LOC
's	O
massive	O
plutonium	O
program	O
.	O

Shaun	B-PER
Bernie	I-PER
of	O
Greenpeace	B-ORG
International	O
said	O
Ozawa	B-PER
is	O
right	O
to	O
state	O
the	O
potential	O
of	O
Japan	B-LOC
to	O
use	O
its	O
so-called	O
peaceful	O
plutonium	O
program	O
for	O
nuclear	O
weapons	O
purposes	O
.	O

Bernie	B-PER
said	O
Ozawa	B-PER
has	O
exposed	O
the	O
myths	O
of	O
Japan	B-LOC
being	O
a	O
peaceful	O
energy	O
program	O
for	O
a	O
resource	O
poor	O
country	O
.	O

Bernie	B-PER
said	O
Ozawa	B-PER
's	O
statement	O
may	O
actually	O
serve	O
an	O
important	O
role	O
in	O
forcing	O
the	O
scale	O
of	O
Japan	B-LOC
's	O
plutonium	O
program	O
and	O
the	O
threat	O
of	O
confrontation	O
in	O
northeast	O
Asia	B-LOC
on	O
to	O
the	O
international	O
agenda	O
.	O

2002-04-08	O

Russian	B-LOC
Federation	I-LOC
(	O
RU	B-MISC
)	O
;	O
Brazil	B-LOC
(	O
BR	B-ORG
)	O

International	O
;	O
weapons	O
;	O
space	O

Brazilian	B-MISC
Defense	O
Minister	O
in	O
Moscow	B-LOC
for	O
cooperation	O
talks	O
with	O
government	O
officials	O
and	O
leading	O
members	O
of	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
military-industrial	O
complex	O
.	O

Emphasized	O
in	O
the	O
discussion	O
is	O
arms	O
sales	O
and	O
extended	O
cooperation	O
in	O
the	O
space	O
sector	O
.	O

Brazilian	B-MISC
embassy	O
officials	O
stated	O
that	O
on	O
8	O
April	O
2002	O
Brazilian	B-MISC
Defense	O
Minister	O
Geraldo	B-PER
da	I-PER
Cruz	I-PER
Quintao	I-PER
began	O
a	O
week-long	O
series	O
of	O
meetings	O
in	O
Moscow	B-LOC
with	O
Russian	B-MISC
officials	O
during	O
which	O
he	O
is	O
to	O
meet	O
Russian	B-MISC
Defense	O
Minister	O
Sergei	B-PER
Ivanov	I-PER
.	O

Quintao	B-PER
met	O
head	O
of	O
the	O
Arms	B-ORG
Export	I-ORG
Company	I-ORG
Rosoboronexport	B-ORG
Andrei	B-PER
Belyaninov	I-PER
.	O

A	O
spokesman	O
for	O
Rosoboronexport	B-ORG
was	O
quoted	O
by	O
the	O
Interfax	B-ORG
news	O
agency	O
as	O
stating	O
that	O
Quintao	B-PER
met	O
Belyaninov	B-PER
to	O
discuss	O
cooperation	O
in	O
various	O
areas	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
the	O
preparation	O
of	O
specific	O
contracts	O
for	O
Russian	B-MISC
arms	O
sales	O
to	O
Brazil	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
spokesman	O
for	O
Rosoboronexport	B-ORG
stated	O
that	O
the	O
discussed	O
cooperation	O
was	O
marked	O
by	O
an	O
emphasis	O
on	O
the	O
space	O
sector	O
.	O

The	O
Brazilian	B-MISC
embassy	O
stated	O
that	O
Quintao	B-PER
is	O
also	O
to	O
meet	O
leading	O
members	O
of	O
Russia	B-LOC
's	O
military-industrial	O
complex	O
.	O

After	O
meeting	O
Ivanov	B-PER
on	O
9	O
April	O
2002	O
Quintao	B-PER
will	O
travel	O
to	O
Saint	B-LOC
Petersburg	I-LOC
where	O
he	O
will	O
spend	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
week	O
.	O

During	O
a	O
visit	O
in	O
January	O
2002	O
by	O
Brazilian	B-MISC
President	O
Fernando	B-PER
Henrique	I-PER
Cardoso	I-PER
and	O
a	O
delegation	O
of	O
70	O
people	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
government	O
stated	O
that	O
it	O
anticipated	O
sales	O
of	O
its	O
Su-27	B-MISC
and	O
MiG-29	O
fighters	O
to	O
Brazil	B-LOC
along	O
with	O
S-300	B-MISC
anti-missile	O
batteries	O
.	O

Brazil	B-LOC
is	O
known	O
to	O
be	O
interested	O
in	O
extending	O
its	O
cooperation	O
with	O
Russia	B-LOC
in	O
the	O
space	O
sector	O
and	O
has	O
offered	O
Russia	B-LOC
the	O
use	O
of	O
a	O
platform	O
in	O
the	O
north	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
for	O
satellite	O
launches	O
.	O

2002-04-08	O

United	B-LOC
Kingdom	I-LOC
(	O
GB	O
)	O

International	O
;	O
Government	O
;	O
weapons	O
;	O
media	O
;	O
technology	O
;	O
terrorism	O
;	O
proliferation	O

Declassified	O
British	B-MISC
Ministry	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Defense	I-ORG
documents	O
explain	O
how	O
Britain	B-LOC
made	O
its	O
first	O
nuclear	O
bomb	O
.	O

Critics	O
state	O
that	O
with	O
access	O
to	O
plutonium	O
available	O
from	O
rogue	O
States	O
terrorists	O
could	O
consult	O
the	O
detailed	O
documents	O
and	O
build	O
an	O
atomic	O
bomb	O
.	O

The	B-ORG
Daily	I-ORG
Telegraph	I-ORG
reported	O
on	O
08	O
April	O
2002	O
that	O
declassified	O
British	B-MISC
Ministry	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Defense	I-ORG
documents	O
explain	O
how	O
to	O
make	O
an	O
atomic	O
bomb	O
.	O

The	B-ORG
Daily	I-ORG
Telegraph	I-ORG
reports	O
that	O
the	O
documents	O
became	O
public	O
domain	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
5	O
years	O
.	O

The	O
declassified	O
documents	O
are	O
available	O
to	O
the	O
public	O
and	O
could	O
therefore	O
be	O
consulted	O
by	O
terrorists	O
.	O

The	B-ORG
Daily	I-ORG
Telegraph	I-ORG
reports	O
that	O
the	O
documents	O
give	O
details	O
of	O
the	O
manufacture	O
of	O
Britain	B-LOC
's	O
first	O
nuclear	O
bomb	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
1940s	O
and	O
start	O
of	O
the	O
1950s	O
.	O

The	O
declassified	O
documents	O
provide	O
a	O
list	O
of	O
the	O
ingredients	O
for	O
such	O
a	O
weapon	O
including	O
the	O
amount	O
of	O
plutonium	O
necessary	O
and	O
how	O
to	O
spark	O
off	O
a	O
chain	O
reaction	O
.	O

Britain	B-LOC
's	O
first	O
nuclear	O
bomb	O
was	O
called	O
Blue	B-LOC
Danube	I-LOC
.	O

Former	O
engineer	O
who	O
worked	O
on	O
Britain	B-LOC
's	O
military	O
nuclear	O
program	O
Brian	B-PER
Burnell	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
instructions	O
could	O
enable	O
a	O
terrorist	O
to	O
construct	O
a	O
rudimentary	O
atomic	O
bomb	O
.	O

The	O
Telegraph	B-ORG
reported	O
that	O
the	O
principle	O
challenge	O
would	O
be	O
obtaining	O
the	O
necessary	O
plutonium	O
but	O
that	O
several	O
outlaw	O
states	O
like	O
Iraq	B-LOC
might	O
possess	O
plutonium	O
.	O

Terror	O
organizations	O
like	O
al-Qaeda	B-ORG
have	O
tried	O
to	O
obtain	O
plutonium	O
.	O

Burnell	B-PER
was	O
quoted	O
as	O
stating	O
that	O
the	O
documents	O
should	O
never	O
have	O
been	O
declassified	O
and	O
after	O
the	O
events	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
2001	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
case	O
for	O
removing	O
them	O
from	O
public	O
access	O
.	O

The	O
Telegraph	B-ORG
stated	O
that	O
opposition	O
Conservative	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
defense	O
spokesman	O
Bernard	B-PER
Jenkin	I-PER
immediately	O
called	O
for	O
explanations	O
from	O
the	O
Labour	B-ORG
government	O
calling	O
the	O
documents	O
a	O
monstrous	O
free	O
gift	O
to	O
terrorists	O
.	O

2002-04-16	O

The	O
majority	O
of	O
the	O
heroin	O
is	O
grown	O
in	O
neighboring	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

In	O
2001	O
the	O
Russian	B-MISC
army	O
and	O
Tajik	B-MISC
police	O
confiscated	O
nearly	O
9	O
tons	O
of	O
drugs	O
and	O
arrested	O
more	O
than	O
2000	O
people	O
.	O

The	O
Russian	B-MISC
army	O
guards	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
's	O
border	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
majority	O
of	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
's	O
heroin	O
addicts	O
live	O
in	O
cities	O
and	O
are	O
aged	O
between	O
18	O
and	O
25	O
.	O

75	O
percent	O
of	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
's	O
population	O
lives	O
in	O
rural	O
areas	O
,	O
where	O
heroin	O
addicts	O
are	O
frequently	O
ostracized	O
.	O

Head	O
of	O
a	O
public	O
drug	O
clinic	O
in	O
Dushanbe	B-LOC
,	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
Andrei	B-PER
Onishchenko	I-PER
,	O
stated	O
--	O

There	O
are	O
5000	O
heroin	O
addicts	O
officially	O
registered	O
in	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
,	O
compared	O
with	O
57	O
in	O
1997	O
.	O

The	O
actual	O
figure	O
is	O
seven	O
times	O
greater	O
than	O
the	O
official	O
number	O
.	O

The	O
low	O
cost	O
and	O
availability	O
of	O
heroin	O
are	O
among	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
the	O
addiction	O
problem	O
.	O

One	O
dose	O
of	O
heroin	O
costs	O
less	O
than	O
a	O
dollar	O
in	O
Tajikistan	B-LOC
,	O
which	O
is	O
less	O
than	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
a	O
bottle	O
of	O
the	O
local	O
vodka	O
.	O

an	O
addict	O
who	O
has	O
been	O
using	O
heroin	O
for	O
2	O
years	O
needs	O
to	O
use	O
3	O
grams	O
of	O
heroin	O
every	O
24	O
hours	O
.	O

3	O
grams	O
of	O
heroin	O
costs	O
70	O
somonis	O
or	O
30	O
dollars	O
.	O

an	O
addict	O
is	O
willing	O
to	O
commit	O
any	O
crime	O
to	O
pay	O
for	O
heroin	O
.	O

Afghan	B-MISC
heroin	O
is	O
the	O
strongest	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
because	O
it	O
is	O
made	O
from	O
poppies	O
cultivated	O
at	O
high	O
altitudes	O
and	O
therefore	O
subjected	O
to	O
high	O
doses	O
of	O
ultra-violet	O
light	O
.	O

A	O
person	O
who	O
takes	O
a	O
daily	O
dose	O
of	O
Afghan	B-MISC
heroin	O
has	O
a	O
life	O
expectancy	O
of	O
between	O
5	O
and	O
7	O
years	O
and	O
many	O
commit	O
suicide	O
before	O
that	O
.	O

The	O
Tajik	B-MISC
State	O
pays	O
25	O
dirams	O
(	O
a	O
few	O
cents	O
)	O
per	O
day	O
for	O
every	O
person	O
in	O
the	O
rehabilitation	O
clinics	O
.	O

The	O
percentage	O
of	O
relapses	O
is	O
very	O
high	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
lack	O
of	O
followup	O
treatment	O
and	O
unemployment	O
among	O
young	O
people	O
.	O

Head	O
of	O
a	O
Tajik	B-MISC
government	O
agency	O
that	O
fights	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
Avaz	B-ORG
yuldachev	O
stated	O
that	O
heroin	O
users	O
are	O
ill	O
and	O
need	O
treatment	O
.	O

Anvar	B-PER
,	O
a	O
14-year-old	O
boy	O
from	O
Dushanbe	B-LOC
,	O
used	O
heroin	O
for	O
three	O
years	O
before	O
being	O
hospitalized	O
in	O
Onishchenko	B-PER
's	O
drug	O
clinic	O
.	O

Anvar	B-PER
said	O
--	O

He	O
sniffed	O
a	O
white	O
substance	O
he	O
found	O
in	O
his	O
backyard	O
and	O
was	O
unable	O
to	O
stop	O
.	O

He	O
stopped	O
going	O
to	O
school	O
.	O

He	O
stole	O
from	O
the	O
local	O
market	O
to	O
get	O
money	O
for	O
more	O
heroin	O
.	O

Drug	O
traffickers	O
face	O
the	O
death	O
penalty	O
under	O
Tajik	B-MISC
law	O
.	O

Tajikistan	B-LOC
has	O
6.2	O
million	O
inhabitants	O
.	O

2002-04-22	O

Thailand	B-LOC
(	O
TH	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
economy	O
;	O
business	O

Southeast	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
nations	O
are	O
collaborating	O
with	O
the	O
European	B-ORG
Union	I-ORG
in	O
the	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
strengthen	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
in	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
with	O
the	O
goal	O
of	O
strengthening	O
business	O
and	O
investor	O
confidence	O
.	O

European	B-ORG
Union	I-ORG
officials	O
stated	O
on	O
April	O
22	O
,	O
2002	O
that	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asians	I-LOC
would	O
boost	O
their	O
trade	O
and	O
investment	O
prospects	O
by	O
introducing	O
stricter	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
.	O

European	B-ORG
Union	I-ORG
officers	O
and	O
the	O
Association	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Southeast	I-ORG
Asian	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
started	O
negotiating	O
how	O
to	O
strengthen	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
.	O

The	O
negotiation	O
began	O
with	O
a	O
two-day	O
workshop	O
in	O
Bangkok	B-LOC
on	O
April	O
22	O
,	O
2002	O
.	O

The	O
negotiation	O
was	O
organized	O
under	O
the	O
new	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
.	O

Head	O
of	O
the	O
delegation	O
of	O
the	O
European	B-ORG
Commission	I-ORG
in	O
Bangkok	B-LOC
Klauspeter	O
schmallenbach	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
comply	O
with	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
rules	O
would	O
help	O
developing	O
nations	O
take	O
part	O
in	O
global	O
trade	O
.	O

Klauspeter	O
schmallenbach	O
stated	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
form	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
basic	O
pillars	O
upon	O
which	O
business	O
and	O
investor	O
confidence	O
are	O
based	O
.	O

Klauspeter	O
schmallenbach	O
also	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
for	O
essential	O
for	O
any	O
country	O
's	O
economic	O
development	O
.	O

Klauspeter	O
schmallenbach	O
stated	O
that	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
may	O
help	O
boost	O
European	B-MISC
investment	O
in	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
to	O
pre-crisis	O
levels	O
.	O

European	B-MISC
patents	O
office	O
President	O
Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
said	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
vital	O
that	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
Nations	I-LOC
introduced	O
proper	O
legal	O
and	O
technical	O
infrastructure	O
to	O
defend	O
trademarks	O
.	O

Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
are	O
currently	O
developing	O
in	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
nations	O
.	O

Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
stated	O
there	O
is	O
larger	O
interest	O
in	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
now	O
than	O
20	O
or	O
30	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O

Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
some	O
nations	O
had	O
stronger	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
than	O
others	O
.	O

Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
also	O
stated	O
that	O
one	O
should	O
not	O
tell	O
the	O
countries	O
that	O
are	O
lagging	O
in	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
lagging	O
in	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
.	O

Director	O
General	O
of	O
Thailand	B-LOC
's	O
Department	O
of	O
intellectual	O
property	O
yanyong	O
phuangranch	O
stated	O
that	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
nations	O
had	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
ensure	O
trademarks	O
were	O
protected	O
.	O

The	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
fosters	O
trade	O
,	O
investment	O
and	O
technology	O
transfer	O
between	O
the	O
European	B-ORG
Union	I-ORG
and	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
nations	O
.	O

Klauspeter	O
schmallenbach	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
would	O
help	O
Southeast	B-MISC
Asian	I-MISC
Nations	I-ORG
draw	O
on	O
European	B-MISC
expertise	O
in	O
how	O
to	O
protect	O
and	O
enforce	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
in	O
compliance	O
with	O
World	B-ORG
Trade	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
rules	O
.	O

50	O
experts	O
in	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
attended	O
the	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
.	O

Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
is	O
further	O
proof	O
of	O
the	O
growing	O
importance	O
of	O
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
protection	O
to	O
world	O
trade	O
.	O

Ingo	B-PER
Kober	I-PER
also	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
European	B-MISC
Commission-ASEAN	B-MISC
intellectual	O
property	O
rights	O
cooperation	O
program	O
marks	O
the	O
latest	O
stage	O
in	O
a	O
successful	O
initiative	O
to	O
develop	O
effective	O
systems	O
for	O
protecting	O
patents	O
,	O
trademarks	O
,	O
designs	O
,	O
and	O
copyrights	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O

2002-04-23	O

Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
(	O
KR	B-LOC
)	O
;	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
(	O
US	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
military	O
;	O
business	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
will	O
provide	O
40	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
jets	O
to	O
the	O
Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
and	O
promises	O
to	O
meet	O
an	O
offset	O
trade	O
level	O
of	O
70	O
percent	O
.	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
promised	O
on	O
April	O
23	O
,	O
2002	O
to	O
fulfill	O
more	O
spin-off	O
orders	O
for	O
companies	O
located	O
in	O
the	O
Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
purpose	O
of	O
this	O
promise	O
is	O
to	O
allow	O
Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
to	O
win	O
a	O
multi-billion	O
dollar	O
fighter	O
jet	O
contract	O
.	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
is	O
required	O
to	O
supply	O
40	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
jets	O
to	O
the	O
Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
by	O
2009	O
.	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
vice	O
president	O
and	O
general	O
manager	O
Michael	B-PER
Marks	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
Government	O
of	O
the	O
Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
decided	O
wisely	O
by	O
picking	O
the	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
instead	O
of	O
the	O
Rafale	B-MISC
made	O
by	O
French	B-MISC
firm	O
Dassault	B-ORG
Aviation	I-ORG
SA	I-ORG
.	O

The	O
final	O
sale	O
price	O
,	O
spin-off	O
trade	O
,	O
and	O
technology	O
transfer	O
conditions	O
will	O
be	O
decided	O
in	O
a	O
future	O
negotiation	O
.	O

The	O
Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
stated	O
that	O
it	O
will	O
argue	O
to	O
decrease	O
the	O
price	O
from	O
an	O
estimated	O
4.4	O
billion	O
dollars	O
.	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
has	O
not	O
yet	O
satisfied	O
a	O
defense	O
ministry	O
demand	O
that	O
spin-off	O
deals	O
with	O
other	O
firms	O
based	O
in	O
the	O
Republic	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Korea	I-LOC
meet	O
70	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
total	O
cost	O
.	O

The	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
initially	O
made	O
a	O
pledge	O
of	O
approximately	O
2.9	O
billion	O
dollars	O
,	O
representing	O
65%	O
of	O
the	O
total	O
cost	O
,	O
to	O
local	O
contractors	O
.	O

Vice	O
president	O
of	O
Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
Joseph	B-PER
Song	I-PER
stated	O
that	O
the	O
70	O
percent	O
offset	O
trade	O
level	O
will	O
be	O
met	O
.	O

Song	O
also	O
stated	O
a	O
level	O
of	O
80	O
percent	O
was	O
possible	O
.	O

Dassault	B-ORG
Aviation	I-ORG
SA	I-ORG
is	O
trying	O
to	O
overturn	O
the	O
selection	O
of	O
the	O
F-15	B-MISC
k	O
through	O
legal	O
action	O
because	O
it	O
states	O
the	O
Rafale	B-MISC
is	O
more	O
modern	O
and	O
cheaper	O
.	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Vice	O
President	O
for	O
communications	O
Douglas	B-PER
Kennett	I-PER
stated	O
disappointment	O
by	O
Dassault	B-ORG
's	O
legal	O
action	O
.	O

Kennett	B-PER
also	O
stated	O
that	O
Dassault	B-ORG
should	O
respect	O
the	O
defense	O
ministry	O
decision	O
.	O

Boeing	B-ORG
Corporation	I-ORG
is	O
an	O
aerospace	O
company	O
based	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-LOC
States	I-LOC
.	O

2002-04-23	O

Cambodia	B-LOC
(	O
KH	O
)	O
;	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
(	O
VN	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
narcotics	O

Cambodia	B-LOC
and	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
finalized	O
an	O
agreement	O
to	O
stop	O
Asian	B-MISC
and	O
European	B-MISC
drug	O
traffickers	O
.	O

On	O
April	O
23	O
,	O
2002	O
Cambodia	B-LOC
and	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
finalized	O
an	O
agreement	O
to	O
stop	O
Asian	B-MISC
and	O
European	B-MISC
drug	O
traffickers	O
.	O

Ramin	B-PER
said	O
the	O
narcotics	O
Authority	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
combat	O
and	O
reduce	O
illegal	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Drug	O
consumption	O
among	O
Cambodian	B-MISC
adolescents	O
has	O
increased	O
.	O

Ecstasy	O
and	O
other	O
drugs	O
are	O
accessible	O
at	O
nightclubs	O
in	O
the	O
capital	O
at	O
a	O
low	O
cost	O
.	O

Cambodia	B-LOC
and	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
agreed	O
to	O
share	O
intelligence	O
,	O
cooperate	O
between	O
agents	O
and	O
create	O
border	O
liaison	O
offices	O
in	O
a	O
two-day	O
meeting	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
later	O
this	O
week	O
.	O

Ramin	B-PER
stated	O
that	O
there	O
is	O
an	O
agreement	O
to	O
construct	O
cross-border	O
liaison	O
offices	O
in	O
both	O
countries	O
to	O
combat	O
current	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

The	O
agreement	O
includes	O
exchanges	O
of	O
experience	O
in	O
organizing	O
treatment	O
and	O
rehabilitation	O
for	O
drug	O
addicts	O
.	O

It	O
would	O
also	O
be	O
used	O
to	O
combat	O
people	O
smuggling	O
between	O
Cambodia	B-LOC
and	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
.	O

Vietnamese	B-MISC
police	O
detained	O
two	O
women	O
on	O
suspicion	O
of	O
human	O
trafficking	O
and	O
smuggling	O
Vietnamese	B-MISC
virgins	O
to	O
Cambodian	B-MISC
brothels	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
less	O
than	O
350	O
dollars	O
each	O
.	O

Cambodia	B-LOC
has	O
for	O
many	O
years	O
been	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
transit	O
point	O
for	O
heroin	O
and	O
opium	O
trafficking	O
.	O

The	O
Government	O
maintains	O
it	O
has	O
adopted	O
strict	O
policies	O
to	O
fight	O
the	O
illegal	O
trading	O
of	O
narcotics	O
.	O

2002-05-17	O

Malaysia	B-LOC
(	O
MY	O
)	O

International	O
;	O
Government	O
;	O
terrorism	O
;	O
crime	O

The	O
statement	O
stated	O
that	O
closer	O
cooperation	O
amongst	O
the	O
nations	O
was	O
needed	O
to	O
counter	O
terrorism	O
.	O

17	O
May	O
2002	O
--	O
in	O
a	O
draft	O
statement	O
the	O
Association	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Southeast	I-ORG
Asian	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
(	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
)	O
agreed	O
closer	O
cooperation	O
was	O
needed	O
to	O
counter	O
terrorism	O
and	O
transnational	O
crime	O
.	O

The	O
statement	O
will	O
be	O
adopted	O
by	O
security	O
ministers	O
next	O
week	O
.	O

An	O
anonymous	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
senior	O
official	O
stated	O
--	O

The	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
ministers'	O
joint	O
statement	O
addressed	O
the	O
need	O
for	O
closer	O
cooperation	O
.	O

Proceeds	O
from	O
organized	O
crime	O
syndicates	O
often	O
fund	O
terrorist	O
activities	O
.	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
has	O
a	O
plan	O
to	O
counter	O
terrorism	O
together	O
.	O

The	O
plan	O
will	O
be	O
implemented	O
within	O
3	O
months	O
.	O

The	O
meeting	O
has	O
been	O
fruitful	O
.	O

The	O
draft	O
statement	O
stated	O
--	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
Ministers	O
are	O
concerned	O
about	O
the	O
links	O
between	O
transnational	O
crime	O
and	O
terrorism	O
.	O

The	O
link	O
between	O
transnational	O
crime	O
and	O
terrorism	O
lends	O
greater	O
urgency	O
to	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
's	O
efforts	O
to	O
combat	O
transnational	O
crime	O
.	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
senior	O
officials	O
agreed	O
on	O
the	O
draft	O
after	O
2	O
days	O
of	O
intense	O
discussion	O
.	O

The	O
draft	O
will	O
be	O
submitted	O
to	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
's	O
respective	O
ministers	O
to	O
discuss	O
and	O
adopt	O
.	O

From	O
19	O
May	O
2002	O
the	O
interior	O
ministers	O
of	O
the	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
countries	O
will	O
meet	O
for	O
2	O
days	O
in	O
Kuala	B-LOC
Lumpur	I-LOC
.	O

The	O
work	O
program	O
includes	O
an	O
exchange	O
of	O
information	O
and	O
development	O
of	O
multilateral	O
or	O
bilateral	O
legal	O
arrangements	O
to	O
facilitate	O
apprehension	O
.	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
officials	O
agreed	O
to	O
enhance	O
cooperation	O
and	O
coordination	O
in	O
law	O
enforcement	O
and	O
intelligence	O
sharing	O
.	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
officials	O
agreed	O
to	O
develop	O
regional	O
training	O
programs	O
.	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
officials	O
held	O
an	O
expert	O
group	O
meeting	O
in	O
January	O
2002	O
in	O
Bali	B-LOC
,	O
Indonesia	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
Expert	B-ORG
Group	I-ORG
Meeting	I-ORG
in	O
Bali	B-LOC
produced	O
a	O
work	O
program	O
that	O
was	O
discussed	O
and	O
finalized	O
by	O
the	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
senior	O
officials	O
who	O
have	O
been	O
meeting	O
in	O
Kuala	B-LOC
Lumpur	I-LOC
since	O
16	O
May	O
2002	O
.	O

The	O
Association	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Southeast	I-ORG
Asian	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
has	O
10	O
member	O
countries	O
.	O

2002-05-17	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
(	O
MM	B-LOC
)	O
;	O
Thailand	B-LOC
(	O
TH	B-LOC
)	O
;	O
Lao	B-ORG
People	I-ORG
's	I-ORG
Democratic	I-ORG
Republic	I-ORG
(	O
LA	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
narcotics	O
;	O
politics	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
is	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
largest	O
producer	O
of	O
illegal	O
opium	O
but	O
has	O
limited	O
financial	O
and	O
technical	O
resources	O
for	O
ending	O
the	O
drug	O
trade	O
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
proposed	O
a	O
ministerial	O
meeting	O
with	O
Thailand	B-LOC
and	O
Laos	B-LOC
to	O
discuss	O
effective	O
ways	O
to	O
end	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
proposed	O
talks	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
in	O
June	O
2002	O
or	O
July	O
2002	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
the	O
US	B-ORG
State	I-ORG
Department	I-ORG
anti-narcotics	O
report	O
published	O
earlier	O
in	O
2002	O
--	O

Following	O
the	O
destruction	O
of	O
poppy	O
fields	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
,	O
Myanmar	B-LOC
has	O
become	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
largest	O
producer	O
of	O
illegal	O
opium	O
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
is	O
the	O
primary	O
source	O
of	O
amphetamine-type	O
stimulants	O
in	O
Asia	B-LOC
.	O

Director	O
of	O
Myanmar	B-LOC
's	O
International	B-ORG
Relations	I-ORG
Department	I-ORG
Colonel	O
sit	O
Aye	B-LOC
addressed	O
reporters	O
at	O
a	O
two-day	O
meeting	O
of	O
senior	O
officials	O
from	O
the	O
Association	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Southeast	I-ORG
Asian	I-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
(	O
ASEAN	B-ORG
)	O
.	O

Aye	B-LOC
announced	O
--	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
,	O
Thailand	B-LOC
and	O
Laos	B-LOC
must	O
cooperate	O
to	O
effectively	O
end	O
the	O
drug	O
trade	O
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
does	O
not	O
yet	O
have	O
confirmation	O
from	O
Thailand	B-LOC
and	O
Laos	B-LOC
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
has	O
difficulty	O
ending	O
drug-planting	O
activities	O
due	O
to	O
lack	O
of	O
funds	O
and	O
technical	O
expertise	O
.	O

The	O
majority	O
of	O
poppy	O
growing	O
in	O
Myanmar	B-LOC
takes	O
place	O
in	O
a	O
remote	O
,	O
mountainous	O
area	O
along	O
the	O
borders	O
of	O
China	B-LOC
and	O
Thailand	B-LOC
.	O

ASEAN	B-ORG
and	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
are	O
responsible	O
to	O
help	O
fight	O
drug	O
production	O
and	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
is	O
optimistic	O
that	O
drug	O
planting	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
would	O
be	O
eradicated	O
with	O
the	O
introduction	O
of	O
alternate	O
cash	O
crop	O
planting	O
in	O
April	O
and	O
tough	O
policing	O
.	O

Fears	O
that	O
drug	O
money	O
is	O
being	O
used	O
to	O
finance	O
terror	O
groups	O
are	O
unfounded	O
.	O

Myanmar	B-LOC
,	O
Thailand	B-LOC
and	O
Laos	B-LOC
are	O
known	O
as	O
the	O
Golden	B-MISC
Triangle	I-MISC
countries	O
.	O

2002-05-18	O

Iran	B-LOC
,	O
Islamic	B-LOC
Republic	I-LOC
of	O
(	O
IR	O
)	O
:	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
(	O
PK	O
)	O
;	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
(	O
AF	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
economy	O
;	O
politics	O

At	O
a	O
UN-sponsored	B-MISC
conference	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
pledged	O
to	O
assist	O
neighboring	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
by	O
increasing	O
private	O
sector	O
activity	O
.	O

On	O
18	O
May	O
2002	O
at	O
a	O
UN-sponsored	B-MISC
conference	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
pledged	O
economic	O
assistance	O
to	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
neighbors	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
plan	O
to	O
increase	O
private	O
sector	O
activity	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Iranian	B-MISC
Finance	O
and	O
Economy	O
Minister	O
tahmaseb	B-PER
Mazaheri	I-PER
announced	O
--	O

Increasing	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
trade	O
with	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
will	O
reinstate	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
economy	O
after	O
23	O
years	O
of	O
war	O
.	O

Key	O
sectors	O
of	O
cooperation	O
between	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
include	O
Oil	O
and	O
Petro-chemical	O
industries	O
,	O
building	O
and	O
road	O
construction	O
,	O
agricultural	O
machinery	O
and	O
manufacturing	O
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
,	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
must	O
collaborate	O
to	O
end	O
the	O
illegal	O
opium	O
trade	O
.	O

Pakistani	B-MISC
Finance	O
and	O
Economy	O
Minister	O
Shaukat	B-PER
Aziz	I-PER
announced	O
--	O

Pakistan	B-LOC
is	O
eager	O
to	O
cooperate	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
in	O
international	O
and	O
regional	O
efforts	O
.	O

Pakistan	B-LOC
has	O
taken	O
steps	O
to	O
facilitate	O
movement	O
of	O
people	O
and	O
goods	O
between	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
for	O
economic	O
reconstruction	O
.	O

Key	O
sectors	O
of	O
cooperation	O
between	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
include	O
agriculture	O
,	O
rural	O
development	O
,	O
civil	O
aviation	O
,	O
finance	O
and	O
banking	O
,	O
engineering	O
services	O
,	O
judicial	O
and	O
legal	O
services	O
and	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
small	O
and	O
medium-sized	O
firms	O
.	O

Pakistan	B-LOC
will	O
offer	O
College	O
places	O
for	O
teachers	O
,	O
doctors	O
,	O
nurses	O
and	O
paramedics	O
.	O

Pakistani	B-MISC
trade	O
with	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
has	O
increased	O
since	O
the	O
war	O
ended	O
.	O

Pakistan	B-LOC
expects	O
private	O
sector	O
activity	O
between	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
to	O
further	O
develop	O
peace	O
.	O

Deputy	O
head	O
of	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
interim	O
government	O
and	O
Minister	O
of	O
Finance	O
Hedayat	B-PER
Amin-Arsala	I-PER
stated	O
--	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
expects	O
private	O
sector	O
activity	O
to	O
aid	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
reconstruction	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
is	O
preparing	O
liberal	O
economic	O
legislation	O
that	O
will	O
facilitate	O
foreign	O
trade	O
and	O
private	O
sector	O
activity	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
seeks	O
political	O
stability	O
,	O
economic	O
development	O
and	O
a	O
legislative	O
and	O
institutional	O
base	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
plans	O
to	O
serve	O
as	O
a	O
bridge	O
between	O
Central	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
Southeast	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
and	O
seeks	O
help	O
from	O
the	O
Economic	B-ORG
Cooperation	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
.	O

Iranian	B-MISC
Foreign	O
Minister	O
Kamal	B-PER
Kharazi	I-PER
stated	O
the	O
meeting	O
must	O
reinforce	O
the	O
friendship	O
and	O
speed	O
up	O
regional	O
cooperation	O
between	O
Iran	B-LOC
,	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
and	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Speakers	O
addressed	O
opium	O
production	O
and	O
trafficking	O
in	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

Opium	O
crops	O
were	O
suppressed	O
by	O
the	O
later	O
rule	O
of	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
.	O

Opium	O
has	O
reemerged	O
since	O
a	O
US-led	B-MISC
military	O
alliance	O
toppled	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
in	O
December	O
2001	O
.	O

Afghan	B-MISC
interim	O
government	O
head	O
Hamid	B-PER
Karzai	I-PER
and	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
promote	O
a	O
crop	O
substitution	O
program	O
for	O
farmers	O
.	O

Head	O
of	O
United	B-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
Development	I-ORG
Program	I-ORG
Mark	B-PER
Malloch	I-PER
Brown	I-PER
announced	O
concerns	O
about	O
Afghan	B-MISC
interim	O
government	O
head	O
Hamid	B-PER
Karzai	I-PER
's	O
ability	O
to	O
police	O
the	O
drug	O
trade	O
.	O

He	O
stated	O
--	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
is	O
in	O
a	O
state	O
of	O
flux	O
.	O

Afghanistan	B-LOC
has	O
security	O
problems	O
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
have	O
long	O
fought	O
over	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
Taliban	B-ORG
ruled	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
from	O
1996-2001	O
.	O

Pakistan	B-LOC
backed	O
the	O
deposed	O
Taliban	B-ORG
.	O

Iran	B-LOC
funded	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
's	O
rebel	O
Northern	B-MISC
Alliance	I-MISC
.	O

The	O
Northern	B-MISC
Alliance	I-MISC
played	O
a	O
major	O
roll	O
in	O
unseating	O
the	O
Taliban	B-ORG
.	O

Together	O
Iran	B-LOC
and	O
Pakistan	B-LOC
have	O
hosted	O
more	O
than	O
3	O
million	O
Afghan	B-MISC
refugees	O
during	O
years	O
of	O
civil	O
war	O
.	O

Afghan	B-MISC
refugees	O
are	O
now	O
starting	O
to	O
return	O
to	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
after	O
civil	O
war	O
.	O

Deputy	O
head	O
of	O
Afghanistan	B-LOC
interim	O
government	O
Hedayat	B-PER
Amin-Arsala	I-PER
visited	O
Tehran	B-LOC
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
.	O

Members	O
of	O
the	O
Economic	B-ORG
Cooperation	I-ORG
Organization	I-ORG
include	O
the	O
Central	B-LOC
Asian	I-LOC
countries	O
and	O
Turkey	B-LOC
.	O

2002-05-21	O

Viet	B-PER
Nam	I-PER
(	O
VN	O
)	O
;	O
Taiwan	B-LOC
(	O
TW	B-LOC
)	O

International	O
;	O
narcotics	O
;	O
crime	O

Taiwan	B-LOC
national	O
executed	O
in	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
for	O
drug	O
manufacture	O
and	O
trafficking	O
.	O

Police	O
in	O
the	O
strict	O
communist	O
country	O
discovered	O
his	O
methamphetamine	O
manufacturing	O
plant	O
disguised	O
as	O
a	O
soap	O
factory	O
and	O
sentenced	O
him	O
to	O
death	O
in	O
1997	O
.	O

On	O
22	O
May	O
2002	O
officials	O
stated	O
that	O
Taiwan	B-LOC
National	O
Chen	B-PER
Chi	I-PER
Tien	I-PER
was	O
executed	O
by	O
firing	O
squad	O
in	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
's	O
8th	O
execution	O
of	O
a	O
foreigner	O
.	O

Chen	B-PER
was	O
sentenced	O
to	O
death	O
in	O
1997	O
for	O
the	O
illegal	O
manufacture	O
of	O
methamphetamines	O
disguised	O
as	O
a	O
soap	O
manufacturing	O
plant	O
.	O

Court	O
officials	O
in	O
the	O
commercial	O
capital	O
stated	O
that	O
Chen	B-PER
was	O
executed	O
in	O
Ho	B-ORG
Chi	I-ORG
Minh	B-LOC
City	I-LOC
on	O
21	O
May	O
2002	O
.	O

The	O
businessman	O
was	O
arrested	O
with	O
several	O
Vietnamese	B-MISC
accomplices	O
in	O
1995	O
after	O
170	O
kilograms	O
(	O
375	O
pounds	O
)	O
of	O
methamphethamine	O
chlorohydrate	O
were	O
found	O
stored	O
in	O
the	O
downtown	O
soap	O
factory	O
Chen	B-PER
had	O
established	O
in	O
1994	O
.	O

Police	O
established	O
that	O
Chen	B-PER
had	O
already	O
exported	O
at	O
least	O
4	O
shipments	O
of	O
the	O
drug	O
before	O
his	O
illegal	O
manufacturing	O
operation	O
was	O
discovered	O
.	O

Chen	B-PER
traveled	O
to	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
regularly	O
since	O
1992	O
.	O

The	O
crystalline	O
amphetamine	O
derivative	O
is	O
Smokable	B-MISC
and	O
has	O
a	O
very	O
large	O
illegal	O
market	O
in	O
East	B-LOC
Asia	I-LOC
.	O
